[
{"question":"A few.","sound":"afew.mp3","answer":"Poucos"},
{"question":"A little.","sound":"alittle.mp3","answer":"Pouco/um pouco"},
{"question":"A long time ago.","sound":"alongtimeago.mp3","answer":"Há muito tempo"},
{"question":"A one way ticket.","sound":"aonewayticket.mp3","answer":"Passagem só de ida"},
{"question":"A round trip ticket.","sound":"aroundtripticket.mp3","answer":"Passagem ida e volta"},
{"question":"About 300 kilometers.","sound":"about300kilometers.mp3","answer":"Mais ou menos 300 quilometros"},
{"question":"Across from the post office.","sound":"acrossfromthepostoffice.mp3","answer":"Do outro lado do correio"},
{"question":"All day.","sound":"allday.mp3","answer":"O dia todo"},
{"question":"Am I pronouncing it correctly?","sound":"amipronouncingitcorrectly.mp3","answer":"E estou pronunciando corretamente?"},
{"question":"Amy is John's girlfriend.","sound":"amyisjohnsgirlfriend.mp3","answer":"A Amy é namorada do John."},
{"question":"And you?","sound":"andyou.mp3","answer":"E você?"},
{"question":"Anything else?","sound":"anythingelse.mp3","answer":"Algo mais? / Mais alguma coisa?"},
{"question":"Are there any concerts?","sound":"arethereanyconcerts.mp3","answer":"Tem algum show?"},
{"question":"Are they coming this evening?","sound":"aretheycomingthisevening.mp3","answer":"Eles virão esta noite?"},
{"question":"Are they the same?","sound":"aretheythesame.mp3","answer":"Eles são iguais? / São as mesmas coisas?"},
{"question":"Are you afraid?","sound":"areyouafraid.mp3","answer":"Você está com medo?"},
{"question":"Are you allergic to anything?","sound":"areyouallergictoanything.mp3","answer":"Você tem alergia a alguma coisa?"},
{"question":"Are you American?","sound":"areyouamerican.mp3","answer":"Você é americano?"},
{"question":"Are you busy?","sound":"areyoubusy.mp3","answer":"Você está ocupado?"},
{"question":"Are you comfortable?","sound":"areyoucomfortable.mp3","answer":"Você está confortável?"},
{"question":"Are you coming this evening?","sound":"areyoucomingthisevening.mp3","answer":"Você vai vir hoje à noite?"},
{"question":"Are you free tonight?","sound":"areyoufreetonight.mp3","answer":"Você está livre hoje à noite?"},
{"question":"Are you going to attend their wedding?","sound":"areyougoingtoattendtheirwedding.mp3","answer":"Você vai ao casamento deles?"},
{"question":"Are you going to help her?","sound":"areyougoingtohelpher.mp3","answer":"Você vai ajudá-la?"},
{"question":"Are you going to take a plane or train?","sound":"areyougoingtotakeaplaneortrain.mp3","answer":"Você vai pegar um avião ou um trem?"},
{"question":"Are you here alone?","sound":"areyouherealone.mp3","answer":"Você vai sozinho?"},
{"question":"Are you hungry?","sound":"areyouherealone.mp3","answer":"Você está com fome?"},
{"question":"Are you married?","sound":"areyoumarried.mp3","answer":"Você é casado?"},
{"question":"Are you okay?","sound":"areyouok.mp3","answer":"Você está bem?"},
{"question":"Are you ready?","sound":"areyouready.mp3","answer":"Você está pronto/a?"},
{"question":"Are you sick?","sound":"areyousick.mp3","answer":"Você está doente?"},
{"question":"Are you sure?","sound":"areyousure.mp3","answer":"Você tem certeza?"},
{"question":"Are you waiting for someone?","sound":"areyouwaitingforsomeone.mp3","answer":"Você está esperando alguém?"},
{"question":"Are you working today?","sound":"areyouworkingtoday.mp3","answer":"Você trabalha hoje?"},
{"question":"Are you working Tomorrow?","sound":"areyouworkingtomorrow.mp3","answer":"Você vai trabalhar amanhã?"},
{"question":"Are your children with you?","sound":"areyourchildrenwithyou.mp3","answer":"Teus filhos estão contigo?"},
{"question":"As soon as possible.","sound":"assoonaspossible.mp3","answer":"Assim que possível."},
{"question":"At 3 o'clock in the afternoon.","sound":"at3oclockintheafternoon.mp3","answer":"Às três da tarde."},
{"question":"At 3 o'clock.","sound":"at3oclock.mp3","answer":"Às três horas."},
{"question":"At 5th street.","sound":"at5thstreet.mp3","answer":"Na quinta rua."},
{"question":"At 7 o'clock at night.","sound":"at7oclockatnight.mp3","answer":"Às sete da noite."},
{"question":"At 7 o'clock in the morning.","sound":"at7oclockinthemorning.mp3","answer":"Às sete da manhã."},
{"question":"At what time did it happen?","sound":"atwhattimedidithappen.mp3","answer":"A que horas aconteceu?"},
{"question":"At what time?","sound":"atwhattime.mp3","answer":"A que horas?"},
{"question":"Be careful driving.","sound":"becarefuldriving.mp3","answer":"Cuidado ao dirigir"},
{"question":"Be careful.","sound":"becareful.mp3","answer":"Cuidado"},
{"question":"Be quiet.","sound":"bequiet.mp3","answer":"Fique quieto"},
{"question":"Behind the bank.","sound":"behinedthebank.mp3","answer":"Atrás do banco"},
{"question":"Bring me my shirt please.","sound":"bringmemyshirtplease.mp3","answer":"Me traga a minha camisa por favor"},
{"question":"Business is good.","sound":"businessisgood.mp3","answer":"O negócio é bom"},
{"question":"Call me.","sound":"callme.mp3","answer":"Me telefona"},
{"question":"Call the police.","sound":"callthepolice.mp3","answer":"Chame a polícia"},
{"question":"Can I access the Internet here?","sound":"caniaccesstheinternethere.mp3","answer":"Posso acessar a internet aqui?"},
{"question":"Can I borrow some money?","sound":"caniborrowsomemoney.mp3","answer":"Posso emprestar algum dinheiro?"},
{"question":"Can I bring my friend?","sound":"canibringafriend.mp3","answer":"Posso trazer meu amigo/minha amiga?"},
{"question":"Can I have a glass of water please?","sound":"canihaveaglassofwaterplease.mp3","answer":"Posso ter um copo com água por favor?"},
{"question":"Can I have a receipt please?","sound":"canihavearecieptplease.mp3","answer":"Posso ter o recibo por favor?"},
{"question":"Can I have the bill please?","sound":"canihavethebillplease.mp3","answer":"Pode me dar a conta por favor?"},
{"question":"Can I help you?","sound":"canihelpyou.mp3","answer":"Posso te ajudar?"},
{"question":"Can I make an appointment for next Wednesday?","sound":"canimakeanappointmentfornextwednesday.mp3","answer":"Posso marcar a consulta para a próxima quarta-feira?"},
{"question":"Can I see your passport please?","sound":"caniseeyourpassportplease.mp3","answer":"Posso ver teu passaporte por favor?"},
{"question":"Can I take a message?","sound":"canitakeamessage.mp3","answer":"Quer deixar uma mensagem?"},
{"question":"Can I try it on?","sound":"canitryiton.mp3","answer":"Posso experimentar?"},
{"question":"Can I use your phone?","sound":"caniuseyourphone.mp3","answer":"Posso usar teu telefone?"},
{"question":"Can it be cheaper?","sound":"canitbecheaper.mp3","answer":"Posso ter um desconto?"},
{"question":"Can we have a menu please.","sound":"canwehaveamenuplease.mp3","answer":"Você pode nos trazer o carápio por favor?"},
{"question":"Can we have some more bread please?","sound":"canwehavesomemorebreadplease.mp3","answer":"Posso ter um pouco de pão por favor?"},
{"question":"Can we sit over there?","sound":"canwesitoverthere.mp3","answer":"Podemos nos sentar ali?"},
{"question":"Can you call back later?","sound":"canyoucallbacklater.mp3","answer":"Você poderia ligar mais tarde?"},
{"question":"Can you call me back later?","sound":"canyoucallmebacklater.mp3","answer":"Você poderia me ligar mais tarde?"},
{"question":"Can you carry this for me?","sound":"canyoucarrythisforme.mp3","answer":"Você pode carregarr isso pra mim?"},
{"question":"Can you do me a favor?","sound":"canyoudomeafavor.mp3","answer":"Você pode me fazer um favor?"},
{"question":"Can you fix this?","sound":"canyoufixthis.mp3","answer":"Você pode consertar isso?"},
{"question":"Can you give me an example?","sound":"canyougivemeanexample.mp3","answer":"Você pode me dar um exemplo?"},
{"question":"Can you help me?","sound":"canyouhelpme.mp3","answer":"Você pode me ajudar?"},
{"question":"Can you hold this for me?","sound":"canyouholdthisforme.mp3","answer":"Você pode segurar isso para mim?"},
{"question":"Can you please say that again?","sound":"canyoupleasesaythatagain.mp3","answer":"Você pode dizer isso novamente por favor?"},
{"question":"Can you recommend a good restaurant?","sound":"canyourecommendagoodrestaurant.mp3","answer":"Você poderia recomendar um bom restaurante?"},
{"question":"Can you repeat that please?","sound":"canyourepeatthatplease.mp3","answer":"Você poderia repetir por favor?"},
{"question":"Can you show me?","sound":"canyoushowme.mp3","answer":"Você pode me mostar?"},
{"question":"Can you speak louder please?","sound":"canyouspeaklouderplease.mp3","answer":"Você poderia falar mais alto por favor?"},
{"question":"Can you swim?","sound":"canyouswim.mp3","answer":"Você sabe nadar?"},
{"question":"Can you throw that away for me?","sound":"canyouthrowthatawayforme.mp3","answer":"Você pode jagar isso fora pra mim?"},
{"question":"Can you translate this for me?","sound":"canyoutranslatethisforme.mp3","answer":"Você pode me traduzir isso?"},
{"question":"Certainly!","sound":"certinly.mp3","answer":"Certamente!"},
{"question":"Cheers!","sound":"cheers.mp3","answer":"Saúde!"},
{"question":"Chicago is very different from Boston.","sound":"chicagoisverydifferentfromboston.mp3","answer":"Chicagoé bem diferente de Boston."},
{"question":"Come here.","sound":"comehere.mp3","answer":"Venha aqui."},
{"question":"Did it snow yesterday?","sound":"diditsnowyesterday.mp3","answer":"Nevou ontem?"},
{"question":"Did you come with your family?","sound":"didyoucomewithyourfamily.mp3","answer":"Você veio com sua família?"},
{"question":"Did you get my email?","sound":"didyougetmyemail.mp3","answer":"Você recebeu meu email?"},
{"question":"Did you send me flowers?","sound":"didyousendmeflowers.mp3","answer":"Você me mandou flores?"},
{"question":"Did you take your medicine?","sound":"didyoutakeyourmedicine.mp3","answer":"Você tomou seu remédio?"},
{"question":"Did your wife like California?","sound":"didyourwifelikecalifornia.mp3","answer":"Sua esposa gostou da Califórnia?"},
{"question":"Do you accept U.S. Dollars?","sound":"doyouacceptusdollars.mp3","answer":"Você aceita dólares?"},
{"question":"Do you believe that?","sound":"doyoubelievethat.mp3","answer":"Você acredita nisso?"},
{"question":"Do you feel better?","sound":"doyoufeelbetter.mp3","answer":"Você se sente melhor?"},
{"question":"Do you go to Florida often?","sound":"doyougotofloridaoften.mp3","answer":"Você vai frequentemente para a Flórida?"},
{"question":"Do you have a boyfriend?","sound":"doyouhaveaboyfriend.mp3","answer":"Você tem namorado?"},
{"question":"Do you have a girlfriend?","sound":"doyouhaveagirlfriend.mp3","answer":"Você tem namorada?"},
{"question":"Do you have a pencil?","sound":"doyouhaveapencil.mp3","answer":"Você tem um lápis?"},
{"question":"Do you have a problem?","sound":"doyouhaveaproblem.mp3","answer":"Você está com um problema?"},
{"question":"Do you have a swimming pool?","sound":"doyouhaveaswimmingpool.mp3","answer":"Você tem piscina?"},
{"question":"Do you have an appointment?","sound":"doyouhaveanappointment.mp3","answer":"Você tem compromisso?"},
{"question":"Do you have another one?","sound":"doyouhaveanotherone.mp3","answer":"Você tem um outro?"},
{"question":"Do you have any children?","sound":"doyouhaveanychildren.mp3","answer":"Você tem filhos?"},
{"question":"Do you have any coffee?","sound":"doyouhaveanycoffee.mp3","answer":"Você tem café?"},
{"question":"Do you have any money?","sound":"doyouhaveanymoney.mp3","answer":"Você tem dinheiro?"},
{"question":"Do you have any vacancies?","sound":"doyouhaveanyvaccancies.mp3","answer":"Você tem férias?"},
{"question":"Do you have anything cheaper?","sound":"doyouhaveanythingcheaper.mp3","answer":"Você tem algo mais barato?"},
{"question":"Do you have enough money?","sound":"doyouhaveenoughmoney.mp3","answer":"Você tem dinheiro suficiente?"},
{"question":"Do you have the number for a taxi?","sound":"doyouhavethenumberforataxi.mp3","answer":"Você tem um telefone de um táxi?"},
{"question":"Do you have this in size 11?","sound":"doyouhavethisinsize11.mp3","answer":"Você tem este no tamanho 11?"},
{"question":"Do you hear that?","sound":"doyouhearthat.mp3","answer":"Você ouviu isso?"},
{"question":"Do you know her?","sound":"doyouknowher.mp3","answer":"Você a conhece?"},
{"question":"Do you know how much it costs?","sound":"doyouknowhowmuchitcosts.mp3","answer":"Você sabe quanto custa?"},
{"question":"Do you know how to cook?","sound":"doyouknowhowtocook.mp3","answer":"Você sabe cozinhar?"},
{"question":"Do you know how to get to the Marriott Hotel?","sound":"doyouknowhowtogettothemarriotthotel.mp3","answer":"Você sabe como chegar no Hotel Marriott?"},
{"question":"Do you know what this means?","sound":"doyouknowwhatthismeans.mp3","answer":"Você sabe o que isso significa?"},
{"question":"Do you know what this says?","sound":"doyouknowwhatthissays.mp3","answer":"Você sabe o que isso diz?"},
{"question":"Do you know where I can get a taxi?","sound":"doyouknowwhereicangetataxi.mp3","answer":"Você sabe onde posso pegar um táxi?"},
{"question":"Do you know where my glasses are?","sound":"doyouknowwheremyglassesare.mp3","answer":"Você sabe onde estão os meus óculos?"},
{"question":"Do you know where she is?","sound":"doyouknowwheresheis.mp3","answer":"Você sabe onde ela está?"},
{"question":"Do you know where there's a store that sells towels?","sound":"doyouknowwheretheresastorethatsellstowels.mp3","answer":"Você sabe onde tem uma loja que vende toalhas?"},
{"question":"Do you like it here?","sound":"doyoulikeithere.mp3","answer":"Você gosta daqui?"},
{"question":"Do you like the book?","sound":"doyoulikethebook.mp3","answer":"Você gosta deste livro?"},
{"question":"Do you like to watch TV?","sound":"doyouliketowatchtv.mp3","answer":"Você gosta de assistir TV?"},
{"question":"Do you like your boss?","sound":"doyoulikeyourboss.mp3","answer":"Você gosta do teu chefe?"},
{"question":"Do you like your co-workers?","sound":"doyoulikeyourcoworkers.mp3","answer":"Você gosta dos teus colegas de trabalho?"},
{"question":"Do you need anything else?","sound":"doyouneedanythingelse.mp3","answer":"Você precisa de mais alguma coisa?"},
{"question":"Do you need anything?","sound":"doyouneedanything.mp3","answer":"Você precisa de alguma coisa?"},
{"question":"Do you play any sports?","sound":"doyouplayanysports.mp3","answer":"Você pratica algum esporte?"},
{"question":"Do you play basketball?","sound":"doyouplaybasketball.mp3","answer":"Você joga basquete?"},
{"question":"Do you sell batteries?","sound":"doyousellbatteries.mp3","answer":"Você vende pilhas?"},
{"question":"Do you sell medicine?","sound":"doyousellmedicine.mp3","answer":"Você vende remédios?"},
{"question":"Do you smoke?","sound":"doyousmoke.mp3","answer":"Você fuma?"},
{"question":"Do you speak English?","sound":"doyouspeakenglish.mp3","answer":"Você fala inglês?"},
{"question":"Do you study English?","sound":"doyoustudyenglish.mp3","answer":"Você estuda inglês?"},
{"question":"Do you take credit cards?","sound":"doyoutakecreditcards.mp3","answer":"Você aceita cartão de crédito?"},
{"question":"Do you think it'll rain today?","sound":"doyouthinkitllraintoday.mp3","answer":"Você acha que vai chover hoje?"},
{"question":"Do you think it's going to rain tomorrow?","sound":"doyouthinkitsgoingtoraintomorrow.mp3","answer":"Você acha que vai chover amanhã?"},
{"question":"Do you think it's possible?","sound":"doyouthinkitspossible.mp3","answer":"Você acha que é possível?"},
{"question":"Do you think you'll be back by 11:30?","sound":"doyouthinkyoullbebackby1130.mp3","answer":"Você acha que estará de volta até às 11:30?"},
{"question":"Do you understand?","sound":"doyouunderstand.mp3","answer":"Você entende?"},
{"question":"Do you want me to come and pick you up?","sound":"doyouwantmetocomeandpickmeup.mp3","answer":"Você quer que eu venha te pegar?"},
{"question":"Do you want to come with me?","sound":"doyouwanttocomewithme.mp3","answer":"Você quer vir comigo?"},
{"question":"Do you want to go to the movies?","sound":"doyouwanttogotothemovies.mp3","answer":"Você quer ir ao cinema?"},
{"question":"Do you want to go with me?","sound":"doyouwanttogowithme.mp3","answer":"Você quer ir comigo?"},
{"question":"Does anyone here speak English?","sound":"doesanyoneherespeakenglish.mp3","answer":"Alguém fala inglês?"},
{"question":"Does he like the school?","sound":"doesheliketheschool.mp3","answer":"Você gosta da escola?"},
{"question":"Does it often snow in the winter in Massachusetts?","sound":"doesitoftensnowinthewinterinmass.mp3","answer":"Geralmente neva em Massachussetts?"},
{"question":"Does this road go to New York?","sound":"doesthisroadgotony.mp3","answer":"Esta estrada vai para Nova Iorque?"},
{"question":"Don't do that.","sound":"dontdothat.mp3","answer":"Não faça isso."},
{"question":"Don't worry.","sound":"dontworry.mp3","answer":"Não se preocupe."},
{"question":"Every week.","sound":"everyweek.mp3","answer":"Toda semana."},
{"question":"Everyday I get up at 6AM.","sound":"everydayigetupat6.mp3","answer":"Todos os dias eu acordo às 6 da manhã."},
{"question":"Everyone knows it.","sound":"everyoneknowsit.mp3","answer":"Todo mundo sabe isso."},
{"question":"Everything is ready.","sound":"everythingisready.mp3","answer":"Está tudo pronto."},
{"question":"Excellent.","sound":"excellent.mp3","answer":"Excelente."},
{"question":"Excuse me, what did you say?","sound":"excusemewhatdidyousay.mp3","answer":"Desculpe-me, o que voce disse?"},
{"question":"Excuse me.","sound":"excuseme.mp3","answer":"Com licença."},
{"question":"Expiration date.","sound":"experationdate.mp3","answer":"Data de vencimento."},
{"question":"Fill it up, please.","sound":"fillitupplease.mp3","answer":"Encha o tanque por favor."},
{"question":"Follow me.","sound":"followme.mp3","answer":"Siga-me"},
{"question":"For how many nights?","sound":"forhowmanynights.mp3","answer":"Por quantas noites?"},
{"question":"Forget it.","sound":"forgetit.mp3","answer":"Esquece."},
{"question":"From here to there.","sound":"fromheretothere.mp3","answer":"Daqui para aí."},
{"question":"From time to time.","sound":"fromtimetotime.mp3","answer":"De tempos em tempos"},
{"question":"Give me a call.","sound":"givemeacall.mp3","answer":"Me telefona"},
{"question":"Give me the pen.","sound":"givemethepen.mp3","answer":"Me dê a caneta."},
{"question":"Go straight ahead.","sound":"gostraightahead.mp3","answer":"Siga em frente."},
{"question":"Good afternoon.","sound":"goodafternoon.mp3","answer":"Boa tarde"},
{"question":"Good evening sir.","sound":"goodeveningsir.mp3","answer":"Boa noite senhor."},
{"question":"Good idea.","sound":"goodidea.mp3","answer":"Boa ideia"},
{"question":"Good Luck.","sound":"goodluck.mp3","answer":"Boa sorte"},
{"question":"Good morning.","sound":"goodmorning.mp3","answer":"Bom dia"},
{"question":"Great.","sound":"great.mp3","answer":"Ótimo"},
{"question":"Happy Birthday.","sound":"happybirthday.mp3","answer":"Feliz aniversário"},
{"question":"Has your brother been to California?","sound":"hasyourbrotherbeentocalifornia.mp3","answer":"O teu irmão já foi à Califórnia?"},
{"question":"Have a good trip.","sound":"haveagoodtrip.mp3","answer":"Tenha uma boa viagem"},
{"question":"Have they met her yet?","sound":"havetheymetheryet.mp3","answer":"Você já a encontrou?"},
{"question":"Have you arrived?","sound":"haveyouarrived.mp3","answer":"Você já chegou?"},
{"question":"Have you been to Boston?","sound":"haveyoubeentoboston.mp3","answer":"Você já esteve em Boston?"},
{"question":"Have you been waiting long?","sound":"haveyoubeenwaitinglong.mp3","answer":"Você está esperando há muito tempo?"},
{"question":"Have you done this before?","sound":"haveyoudonethisbefore.mp3","answer":"Você já fez isso antes?"},
{"question":"Have you eaten at that restaurant?","sound":"haveyoueatenatthatrestaurant.mp3","answer":"Você já comeu num restaurante?"},
{"question":"Have you eaten yet?","sound":"haveyoueatenyet.mp3","answer":"Você já comeu?"},
{"question":"Have you ever had Potato soup?","sound":"haveyoueverhadpotatosoup.mp3","answer":"Você já comeu sopa de batata?"},
{"question":"Have you finished studying?","sound":"haveyoufinishedstudying.mp3","answer":"Você já acabou de estudar?"},
{"question":"Have you seen this movie?","sound":"haveyouseenthismovie.mp3","answer":"Você já assistiu este filme?"},
{"question":"He always does that for me.","sound":"healwaysdoesthatforme.mp3","answer":"Ele sempre faz isso pra mim."},
{"question":"He broke the window.","sound":"hebrokethewindow.mp3","answer":"Ele quebrou a janela."},
{"question":"He doesn't look like a nurse.","sound":"hedoesntlooklikeanurse.mp3","answer":"Ele não parece um enfermeiro."},
{"question":"He has a nice car.","sound":"hehasanicecar.mp3","answer":"Ele tem um ótimo carro."},
{"question":"He likes it very much.","sound":"helikesitverymuch.mp3","answer":"Ele gosta muito."},
{"question":"He likes juice but he doesn't like milk","sound":"helikesjuicebuthedoesntlikemilk.mp3","answer":"Ele gosta de suco mas não gosta de leite."},
{"question":"He needs some new clothes.","sound":"heneedssomenewclothes.mp3","answer":"Ele precisa de roupas novas."},
{"question":"He never gives me anything.","sound":"henevergivesmeanything.mp3","answer":"Ele nunca me dá nada"},
{"question":"He said this is a nice place.","sound":"hesaidthisisaniceplace.mp3","answer":"Ele disse que este é um ótimo lugar."},
{"question":"He said you like to watch movies.","sound":"hesaidyouliketowatchmovies.mp3","answer":"Ele disse que você gosta de assistir filmes."},
{"question":"He studies at Boston University.","sound":"hestudiesatbostonuniversity.mp3","answer":"Ele estuda na Universidade de Boston."},
{"question":"He thinks we don't want to go.","sound":"hethinkswedontwanttogo.mp3","answer":"Ele acha que nós não queremos ir."},
{"question":"He works at a computer company in New York.","sound":"heworksatacomputercompanyinny.mp3","answer":"Ele trabalha numa empresa em Nova Iorque."},
{"question":"He'll be back in 20 minutes.","sound":"hellbebackin20minutes.mp3","answer":"Ele volta em 20 minutos."},
{"question":"Hello.","sound":"hello.mp3","answer":"Alô."},
{"question":"Help!","sound":"help.mp3","answer":"Socorro!"},
{"question":"Here is your salad.","sound":"heresyoursalad.mp3","answer":"Aqui está sua salada"},
{"question":"Here it is.","sound":"hereitis.mp3","answer":"Aqui está."},
{"question":"Here you are.","sound":"hereyouare.mp3","answer":"Aqui está."},
{"question":"Here's my number.","sound":"heresmynumber.mp3","answer":"Aqui está meu telefone"},
{"question":"Here's your order.","sound":"heresyourorder.mp3","answer":"Aqui está o seu pedido"},
{"question":"He's a very good student.","sound":"hesaverygoodstudent.mp3","answer":"Ele é um bom aluno"},
{"question":"He's an American.","sound":"hesanamerican.mp3","answer":"Ele é americano"},
{"question":"He's an Engineer.","sound":"hesanengineer.mp3","answer":"Ele é engenheiro"},
{"question":"He's coming soon.","sound":"hescomingsoon.mp3","answer":"Ele volta logo"},
{"question":"He's faster than me.","sound":"hesfasterthanme.mp3","answer":"Elé mais rápido do que eu"},
{"question":"He's in the kitchen.","sound":"hesinthekitchen.mp3","answer":"Ele está na cozinha"},
{"question":"He's never been to America.","sound":"hesneverbeentoamerica.mp3","answer":"Ele nunca esteve na América"},
{"question":"He's not in right now.","sound":"hesnotinrightnow.mp3","answer":"Ele não está agora"},
{"question":"He's right.","sound":"hesright.mp3","answer":"Ele está certo."},
{"question":"He's very annoying.","sound":"hesveryannoying.mp3","answer":"Ele está aborrecido."},
{"question":"He's very famous.","sound":"hesveryfamous.mp3","answer":"Ele é muito famoso."},
{"question":"He's very hard working.","sound":"hesveryhardworking.mp3","answer":"Ele é um trabalhador duro."},
{"question":"Hi, is Mrs. Smith there, please?","sound":"hiismrssmiththereplease.mp3","answer":"Oi, a Sra. Smith está, por favor?"},
{"question":"His family is coming tomorrow.","sound":"hisfamilyiscomingtomorrow.mp3","answer":"A família dele vem amanhã."},
{"question":"His room is very small.","sound":"hisroomisverysmall.mp3","answer":"O quarto dele é bem pequeno."},
{"question":"His son.","sound":"hisson.mp3","answer":"Filho dele."},
{"question":"How about Saturday?","sound":"howaboutsaturday.mp3","answer":"Que tal sábado?"},
{"question":"How are you paying?","sound":"howareyoupaying.mp3","answer":"Como você vai pagar?"},
{"question":"How are you?","sound":"howareyou.mp3","answer":"Como vai você?"},
{"question":"How are your parents?","sound":"howareyourparents.mp3","answer":"Como estão teus pais?"},
{"question":"How do I get there?","sound":"howdoigetthere.mp3","answer":"Como eu chego lá?"},
{"question":"How do I get to Daniel Street?","sound":"howdoigettodanielstreet.mp3","answer":"Como eu chego na rua Daniel?"},
{"question":"How do I get to the American Embassy?","sound":"howdoigettotheamericanembassy.mp3","answer":"Como eu chego na Embaixada Americana?"},
{"question":"How do I use this?","sound":"howdoiusethis.mp3","answer":"Como eu uso isto?"},
{"question":"How do you know?","sound":"howdoyouknow.mp3","answer":"Como você sabe?"},
{"question":"How do you pronounce that?","sound":"howdoyoupronouncethat.mp3","answer":"Como você pronuncia isso?"},
{"question":"How do you say it in English?","sound":"howdoyousayitinenglish.mp3","answer":"Como você diz isso em inglês?"},
{"question":"How do you spell it?","sound":"howdoyouspellit.mp3","answer":"Como você soletra isso?"},
{"question":"How do you spell the word Seattle?","sound":"howdoyouspellthewordseattle.mp3","answer":"Como você soletra a palavra Seattle?"},
{"question":"How does it taste?","sound":"howdoesittaste.mp3","answer":"Como está o sabor?"},
{"question":"How far is it to Chicago?","sound":"howfarisittochicago.mp3","answer":"Quão longe é Chicago?"},
{"question":"How far is it?","sound":"howfarisit.mp3","answer":"Quanto longe?"},
{"question":"How is she?","sound":"howisshe.mp3","answer":"Como ela está?"},
{"question":"How long are you going to stay in California?","sound":"howlongareyougoingtostayincalifornia.mp3","answer":"Quanto tempo você vai ficar na Califórnia?"},
{"question":"How long are you going to stay?","sound":"howlongareyougoingtostay.mp3","answer":"Quanto tempo você vai ficar?"},
{"question":"How long does it take by car?","sound":"howlongdoesittakebycar.mp3","answer":"Quanto tempo demora de carro?"},
{"question":"How long does it take to get to Georgia?","sound":"howlongdoesittaketogettogeorgia.mp3","answer":"Quanto tempo demora pra chegar na Georgia?"},
{"question":"How long have you been here?","sound":"howlonghaveyoubeenhere.mp3","answer":"Há quanto tempo você está aqui?"},
{"question":"How long have you been in America?","sound":"howlonghaveyoubeeninamerica.mp3","answer":"Há quanto tempo você está na América?"},
{"question":"How long have you lived here?","sound":"howlonghaveyoulivedhere.mp3","answer":"Há quanto tempo você vive aqui?"},
{"question":"How long have you worked here?","sound":"howlonghaveyouworkedhere.mp3","answer":"Há quanto tempo você trabalha aqui?"},
{"question":"How long is it?","sound":"howlongisit.mp3","answer":"Quanto tempo demora?"},
{"question":"How long is the flight?","sound":"howlongistheflight.mp3","answer":"Quanto tempo demora o voo?"},
{"question":"How long will it take?","sound":"howlongwillittake.mp3","answer":"Quanto tempo vai levar?"},
{"question":"How long will you be staying?","sound":"howlongwillyoubestaying.mp3","answer":"Quanto tempo você vai ficar?"},
{"question":"How many children do you have?","sound":"howmanychildrendoyouhave.mp3","answer":"Quantos filhos você tem?"},
{"question":"How many hours a week do you work?","sound":"howmanyhoursaweekdoyouwork.mp3","answer":"Quantas horas por semana voce trabalha?"},
{"question":"How many languages do you speak?","sound":"howmanylanguagesdoyouspeak.mp3","answer":"Quantos idiomas você fala?"},
{"question":"How many miles is it to Pennsylvania?","sound":"howmanymilesisittopenn.mp3","answer":"Quantas milhas são até Pensilvânia?"},
{"question":"How many people are there in New York?","sound":"howmanypeoplearethereinny.mp3","answer":"Quantas pessoas tem em Nova Iorque"},
{"question":"How many people do you have in your family?","sound":"howmanypeopledoyouhaveinyourfamily.mp3","answer":"Quantas pessoas tem na tua família?"},
{"question":"How many people?","sound":"howmanypeople.mp3","answer":"Para quantas pessoas? (restaurante)"},
{"question":"How many?","sound":"howmany.mp3","answer":"Quantos/quantas"},
{"question":"How much altogether?","sound":"howmuchalltogether.mp3","answer":"Quanto custa tudo junto?"},
{"question":"How much are these earrings?","sound":"howmucharetheseearrings.mp3","answer":"Quanto custam estes brincos?"},
{"question":"How much do I owe you?","sound":"howmuchdoioweyou.mp3","answer":"Quanto eu te devo?"},
{"question":"How much does it cost per day?","sound":"howmuchdoesitcostperday.mp3","answer":"Quanto custa por dia?"},
{"question":"How much does this cost?","sound":"howmuchdoesthiscost.mp3","answer":"Quanto custa isto?"},
{"question":"How much is it to go to Miami?","sound":"howmuchisittogotomiami.mp3","answer":"Quanto custa para ir a Miami?"},
{"question":"How much is it?","sound":"howmuchisit.mp3","answer":"Quanto custa?"},
{"question":"How much is that?","sound":"howmuchisthat.mp3","answer":"Quanto custa isso?"},
{"question":"How much is this?","sound":"howmuchisthis.mp3","answer":"Quanto custa isto?"},
{"question":"How much money do you have?","sound":"howmuchmoneydoyouhave.mp3","answer":"Quanto dinheiro você tem?"},
{"question":"How much money do you make?","sound":"howmuchmoneydoyoumake.mp3","answer":"Quanto dinheiro você ganha?"},
{"question":"How much will it cost?","sound":"howmuchwillitcost.mp3","answer":"Quanto vai custar?"},
{"question":"How much would you like?","sound":"howmuchwouldyoulike.mp3","answer":"Quanto você gostaria?"},
{"question":"How old are you?","sound":"howoldareyou.mp3","answer":"Quantos anos você tem?"},
{"question":"How tall are you?","sound":"howtallareyou.mp3","answer":"Quanto você mede?"},
{"question":"How was the movie?","sound":"howwasthemovie.mp3","answer":"Como foi o filme?"},
{"question":"How was the trip?","sound":"howwasthetrip.mp3","answer":"Como foi a viagem?"},
{"question":"How's business?","sound":"howsbusiness.mp3","answer":"Como estão os negócios?"},
{"question":"How's the weather?","sound":"howstheweather.mp3","answer":"Como está o tempo?"},
{"question":"How's work going?","sound":"howsworkgoing.mp3","answer":"Como vai o trabalho?"},
{"question":"Hurry!","sound":"hurry.mp3","answer":"Depressa!"},
{"question":"I agree.","sound":"iagree.mp3","answer":"Eu concordo."},
{"question":"I ate already.","sound":"iatealready.mp3","answer":"Eu já comí."},
{"question":"I believe you.","sound":"ibelieveyou.mp3","answer":"Eu acredito em você."},
{"question":"I bought a shirt yesterday.","sound":"iboughtashirtyesterday.mp3","answer":"Eu comprei uma camisa ontem."},
{"question":"I came with my family.","sound":"icamewithmyfamily.mp3","answer":"Eu vim com minha famiília."},
{"question":"I can swim.","sound":"icanswim.mp3","answer":"Eu sei nadar."},
{"question":"I can't hear you clearly.","sound":"icanthearyouclearly.mp3","answer":"Eu posso te ouvir claramente."},
{"question":"I can't hear you.","sound":"icanthearyou.mp3","answer":"Eu não te ouço."},
{"question":"I don't care.","sound":"idontcare.mp3","answer":"Eu não me importo."},
{"question":"I don't feel well.","sound":"idontfeelwell.mp3","answer":"Eu não me sinto bem."},
{"question":"I don't have a girlfriend.","sound":"idonthaveagirlfriend.mp3","answer":"Eu não tenho namorada."},
{"question":"I don't have any money.","sound":"idonthaveanymoney.mp3","answer":"Eu não tenho dinheiro."},
{"question":"I don't have enough money.","sound":"idonthaveenoughmoney.mp3","answer":"Eu não tenho dinheiro suficiente."},
{"question":"I don't have time right now.","sound":"idonthavetimerightnow.mp3","answer":"Eu não tenho tempo agora"},
{"question":"I don't know how to use it.","sound":"idontknowhowtouseit.mp3","answer":"Eu não sei como usar isto."},
{"question":"I don't know.","sound":"idontknow.mp3","answer":"Eu não sei."},
{"question":"I don't like him.","sound":"idontlikehim.mp3","answer":"Eu não gosto dele."},
{"question":"I don't like it.","sound":"idontlikeit.mp3","answer":"Eu não gosto."},
{"question":"I don't mind.","sound":"idontmind.mp3","answer":"Eu não me importo."},
{"question":"I don't speak English very well.","sound":"idontspeakenglishverywell.mp3","answer":"Eu não falo inglês muito bem."},
{"question":"I don't speak very well.","sound":"idontspeakverywell.mp3","answer":"Eu não falo muito bem."},
{"question":"I don't think so.","sound":"idontthinkso.mp3","answer":"Eu acho que não."},
{"question":"I don't understand what your saying.","sound":"idontunderstandwhatyoursaying.mp3","answer":"Eu não entendo o que você está dizendo."},
{"question":"I don't understand.","sound":"idontunderstand.mp3","answer":"Eu não entendo."},
{"question":"I don't want it.","sound":"idontwantit.mp3","answer":"Eu não quero."},
{"question":"I don't want that.","sound":"idontwantthat.mp3","answer":"Eu não quero isso."},
{"question":"I don't want to bother you.","sound":"idontwanttobotheryou.mp3","answer":"Eu não quero te incomodar."},
{"question":"I feel good.","sound":"ifeelgood.mp3","answer":"Eu me sinto bem."},
{"question":"I forget.","sound":"iforget.mp3","answer":"Eu esqueço."},
{"question":"I get off of work at 6.","sound":"igetoffworkat6.mp3","answer":"Eu saio do trabalho às 6."},
{"question":"I give up.","sound":"igiveup.mp3","answer":"Eu desisto."},
{"question":"I got in an accident.","sound":"igotinanaccident.mp3","answer":"Eu sofrí um acidente."},
{"question":"I have a cold.","sound":"ihaveacold.mp3","answer":"Eu estou gripado."},
{"question":"I have a headache.","sound":"ihaveaheadache.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho dor de cabeça."},
{"question":"I have a lot of things to do.","sound":"ihavealotofthingstodo.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho um monte de coisas pra fazer."},
{"question":"I have a question I want to ask you./ I want to ask you a question.","sound":"ihaveaquestioniwanttoaskyou.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho uma pergunta para fazer pra você/Eu quero te perguntar uma coisa."},
{"question":"I have a reservation.","sound":"ihaveareservation.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho uma reserva."},
{"question":"I have money.","sound":"ihavemoney.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho dinheiro."},
{"question":"I have one in my car.","sound":"ihaveoneinmycar.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho um/uma no meu carro."},
{"question":"I have pain in my arm.","sound":"ihavepaininmyarm.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho dor no meu braço."},
{"question":"I have three children, two girls and one boy.","sound":"ihavethreechildrentwogirlsandoneboy.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho três filhos, duas meninas e um menino."},
{"question":"I have to go to the post office.","sound":"ihavetogotothepostoffice.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho que ir ao correio."},
{"question":"I have to wash my clothes.","sound":"ihavetowashmyclothes.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho que lavar minhas roupas."},
{"question":"I have two sisters.","sound":"ihave2sisters.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho duas irmãs."},
{"question":"I haven't been there.","sound":"ihaventbeenthere.mp3","answer":"Eu nunca estive lá"},
{"question":"I haven't finished eating.","sound":"ihaventfinishedeating.mp3","answer":"Eu não acabei de comer."},
{"question":"I haven't had lunch yet.","sound":"ihaventhadlunchyet.mp3","answer":"Eu ainda não almocei."},
{"question":"I hope you and your wife have a nice trip.","sound":"ihopeyouandyourwifehaveanicetrip.mp3","answer":"Eu espero que você e tua esposa tenham uma boa viagem."},
{"question":"I know.","sound":"iknow.mp3","answer":"Eu sei."},
{"question":"I like her.","sound":"ilikeher.mp3","answer":"Eu gosto dela."},
{"question":"I like it.","sound":"ilikeit.mp3","answer":"Eu gosto."},
{"question":"I like Italian food.","sound":"ilikeitalianfood.mp3","answer":"Eu gosto de comida italiana."},
{"question":"I like to watch TV.","sound":"iliketowatchtv.mp3","answer":"Eu gosto de assistir TV."},
{"question":"I live in California.","sound":"iliveincalifornia.mp3","answer":"Eu moro na Califórnia."},
{"question":"I lost my watch.","sound":"ilostmywatch.mp3","answer":"Eu perdí meu relógio."},
{"question":"I love you.","sound":"iloveyou.mp3","answer":"Eu amo você."},
{"question":"I made a mistake.","sound":"imadeamistake.mp3","answer":"Eu cometí um erro."},
{"question":"I made this cake.","sound":"imadethiscake.mp3","answer":"Eu fiz este bolo."},
{"question":"I need a doctor.","sound":"ineedadoctor.mp3","answer":"Eu preciso de um médico."},
{"question":"I need another key.","sound":"ineedanotherkey.mp3","answer":"Eu preciso de uma outra chave."},
{"question":"I need some tissues.","sound":"ineedsometissues.mp3","answer":"Eu preciso de uns lenços."},
{"question":"I need this to get there by tomorrow.","sound":"ineedthistogettherebytomorrow.mp3","answer":"Eu preciso que isso chegue lá amanha."},
{"question":"I need to change clothes.","sound":"ineedtochangeclothes.mp3","answer":"Eu preciso trocar de roupas."},
{"question":"I need to go home.","sound":"ineedtogohome.mp3","answer":"Eu preciso ir pra casa."},
{"question":"I need to go now.","sound":"ineedtogonow.mp3","answer":"Eu preciso ir agora."},
{"question":"I need to practice my English.","sound":"ineedtopracticemyenglish.mp3","answer":"Eu preciso praticar meu inglês."},
{"question":"I only have 5 dollars.","sound":"ionlyhave5dollars.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho somente 5 dólares."},
{"question":"I only want a snack.","sound":"ionlywantasnack.mp3","answer":"Eu só quero um lanche."},
{"question":"I remember.","sound":"iremember.mp3","answer":"Eu me lembro."},
{"question":"I speak a little English.","sound":"ispeakalittleenglish.mp3","answer":"Eu falo um pouco de inglês."},
{"question":"I speak two languages.","sound":"ispeak2languages.mp3","answer":"Eu falo dois idiomas."},
{"question":"I still have a lot of things to buy.","sound":"istillhavealotofthingstobuy.mp3","answer":"Eu ainda tenho muitas coisas pra comprar."},
{"question":"I still have a lot to do.","sound":"istillhavealotofworktodo.mp3","answer":"Eu ainda tenho muito que fazer."},
{"question":"I still have to brush my teeth and take a shower.","sound":"istillhavetobrushmyteethandtakeashower.mp3","answer":"Eu ainda tenho que escovar os dentes e tomar um banho."},
{"question":"I still haven't decided.","sound":"istillhaventdecided.mp3","answer":"Eu ainda não decidí."},
{"question":"I think I need to see a doctor.","sound":"ithinkineedtoseeadoctor.mp3","answer":"Eu acho que eu preciso ir ao médico."},
{"question":"I think it tastes good.","sound":"ithinkittastesgood.mp3","answer":"Eu acho isso bem saboroso."},
{"question":"I think it's very good.","sound":"ithinkitsverygood.mp3","answer":"Eu acho isso muito bom"},
{"question":"I think so.","sound":"ithinkso.mp3","answer":"Eu acho que sim."},
{"question":"I think those shoes are very good looking.","sound":"ithinkthoseshoesareverygoodlooking.mp3","answer":"Eu acho aqueles sabatos bem atraentes."},
{"question":"I think you have too many clothes.","sound":"ithinkyouhavetoomanyclothes.mp3","answer":"Eu acho que você tem muitas roupas."},
{"question":"I thought he said something else.","sound":"ithoughthesaidsomethingelse.mp3","answer":"Eu pensei que ele disse outra coisa."},
{"question":"I thought the clothes were cheaper.","sound":"ithoughttheclotheswerecheaper.mp3","answer":"Eu pensei que as roupas eram mais baratas."},
{"question":"I trust you.","sound":"itrustyou.mp3","answer":"Eu confio em você"},
{"question":"I understand now.","sound":"iunderstandnow.mp3","answer":"Eu compreendo agora."},
{"question":"I understand.","sound":"iunderstand.mp3","answer":"Eu entendo."},
{"question":"I usually drink coffee at breakfast.","sound":"iusuallydrinkcoffeeatbreakfast.mp3","answer":"Eu geralmente tomo um cafezinho no café da manhã."},
{"question":"I want to buy something.","sound":"iwanttobuysomething.mp3","answer":"Eu quero comprar alguma coisa."},
{"question":"I want to contact our embassy.","sound":"iwanttocontactourembassy.mp3","answer":"Eu quero contatar nossa embaixada."},
{"question":"I want to give you a gift.","sound":"iwanttogiveyouagift.mp3","answer":"Eu quero te dar um presente."},
{"question":"I want to send this package to the United States.","sound":"iwanttosendthispackagetotheunitedstates.mp3","answer":"Eu quero mandar este pacote para os Estados Unidos."},
{"question":"I want to show you something.","sound":"iwanttoshowyousomething.mp3","answer":"Eu quero te mostrar uma coisa."},
{"question":"I was about to leave the restaurant when my friends arrived.","sound":"iwasabouttoleavetherestaurantwhenmyfriendsarrived.mp3","answer":"Eu estava saindo do restaurante quando meus amigos chegaram."},
{"question":"I was going to the library.","sound":"iwasgoingtothelibrary.mp3","answer":"Eu estava indo à biblioteca."},
{"question":"I was in the library.","sound":"iwasinthelibrary.mp3","answer":"Eu estava na biblioteca."},
{"question":"I went to the supermarket, and then to the computer store.","sound":"iwenttothesupermarketandthentothecomputerstore.mp3","answer":"Eu fui ao supermercado e depois à loja de computador."},
{"question":"I wish I had one.","sound":"iwishihadone.mp3","answer":"Quisera eu tivesse um."},
{"question":"I'd like a map of the city.","sound":"idlikeamapofthecity.mp3","answer":"Eu queria um mapa da cidade."},
{"question":"I'd like a non-smoking room.","sound":"idlikeanonsmokingroom.mp3","answer":"Eu queria um quarto de não fumante."},
{"question":"I'd like a room with two beds please.","sound":"idlikearoomwith2bedsplease.mp3","answer":"Eu queria um quarto com duas camas por favor."},
{"question":"I'd like a room.","sound":"idlikearoom.mp3","answer":"Eu queria um quarto."},
{"question":"I'd like a single room.","sound":"idlikeasingleroom.mp3","answer":"Eu queria um quarto de solteiro."},
{"question":"I'd like a table near the window.","sound":"idlikeatablenearthewindow.mp3","answer":"Eu queria uma mesa perto da janela."},
{"question":"I'd like some water too, please.","sound":"idlikesomewatertooplease.mp3","answer":"Eu também queria um pouco de água, por favor."},
{"question":"I'd like the number for the Hilton Hotel please.","sound":"idlikethenumberforthehiltonhotelplease.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria do telefone do Hotel Hilton, por favor."},
{"question":"I'd like to buy a bottle of water, please.","sound":"idliketobuyabottleofwaterplease.mp3","answer":"Eu queria comprar uma garrafa de água, por favor."},
{"question":"I'd like to buy a phone card please.","sound":"idliketobuyaphonecardplease.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de comprar um cartão telefônico, por favor."},
{"question":"I'd like to buy something.","sound":"idliketobuysomething.mp3","answer":"Eu queria comprar alguma coisa."},
{"question":"I'd like to call the United States.","sound":"idliketocalltheunitedstates.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de ligar para os Estados Unidos."},
{"question":"I'd like to eat at 5th street restaurant.","sound":"idliketoeatat5thstreetrestaurant.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de comer no restaurante da quinta rua."},
{"question":"I'd like to exchange this for Dollars.","sound":"idliketoexchangethisfordollars.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de trocar isto por dólares."},
{"question":"I'd like to go for a walk.","sound":"idliketogoforawalk.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de ir caminhar."},
{"question":"I'd like to go home.","sound":"idliketogohome.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de ir para casa."},
{"question":"I'd like to go shopping.","sound":"idliketogoshopping.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de ir às compras."},
{"question":"I'd like to go to the store.","sound":"idliketogotothestore.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de ir à loja."},
{"question":"I'd like to make a phone call.","sound":"idliketomakeaphonecall.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de fazer um telefonema."},
{"question":"I'd like to make a reservation.","sound":"idliketomakeareservation.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de fazer uma reserva."},
{"question":"I'd like to rent a car.","sound":"idliketorentacar.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de alugar um carro."},
{"question":"I'd like to send a fax.","sound":"idliketosendafax.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de enviar um fax."},
{"question":"I'd like to send this to America.","sound":"idliketosendthistoamerica.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de enviar isto à América."},
{"question":"I'd like to speak to Mr. Smith please.","sound":"idliketospeaktomrsmithplease.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de falar com o Sr. Smith, por favor."},
{"question":"I'd like to use the internet","sound":"idliketousetheinternet.mp3","answer":"Eu gostaria de usar a Internet."},
{"question":"If you like it I can buy more.","sound":"ifyoulikeiticanbuymore.mp3","answer":"Se você gosta eu posso comprar mais."},
{"question":"If you need my help, please let me know.","sound":"ifyouneedmyhelppleaseletmeknow.mp3","answer":"Se você precisa de minha ajuda, por favor me diga."},
{"question":"I'll be right back.","sound":"illberightback.mp3","answer":"Eu volto logo."},
{"question":"I'll call back later.","sound":"illcallbacklater.mp3","answer":"Eu ligo mais tarde."},
{"question":"I'll call you on Friday.","sound":"illcallyouonfriday.mp3","answer":"Eu te ligo na sexta,"},
{"question":"I'll call you when I leave.","sound":"illcallyouwhenileave.mp3","answer":"Eu te ligo quando sair."},
{"question":"I'll come back later.","sound":"illcomebacklater.mp3","answer":"Eu volto mais tarde."},
{"question":"I'll give you a call.","sound":"illgiveyouacall.mp3","answer":"Eu te dou uma ligada."},
{"question":"I'll have a cup of tea please.","sound":"illhaveacupofteaplease.mp3","answer":"Eu quero uma xícara de chá por favor."},
{"question":"I'll have a glass of water please.","sound":"illhaveaglassofwaterplease.mp3","answer":"Eu quero um copo com água por favor."},
{"question":"I'll have the same thing.","sound":"illhavethesamething.mp3","answer":"Eu quero a mesma coisa."},
{"question":"I'll pay for dinner.","sound":"illpayfordinner.mp3","answer":"Eu pagarei o jantar."},
{"question":"I'll pay for the tickets.","sound":"illpayforthetickets.mp3","answer":"Eu pagarei os ingressos."},
{"question":"I'll pay.","sound":"illpay.mp3","answer":"Eu pagarei."},
{"question":"I'll take it.","sound":"illtakeit.mp3","answer":"Eu levo/Eu fico (com alguma coisa)"},
{"question":"I'll take that one also.","sound":"illtakethatonealso.mp3","answer":"Eu vou levar aquele também."},
{"question":"I'll take you to the bus stop.","sound":"illtakeyoutothebusstop.mp3","answer":"Eu te levo ao ponto de ônibus."},
{"question":"I'll talk to you soon.","sound":"illtalktoyousoon.mp3","answer":"Eu falo com você em breve."},
{"question":"I'll teach you.","sound":"illteachyou.mp3","answer":"Eu te ensinarei."},
{"question":"I'll tell him you called.","sound":"illtellhimyoucalled.mp3","answer":"Eu direi a ele que você ligou."},
{"question":"I'm 26 years old.","sound":"im26yearsold.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho 26 anos."},
{"question":"I'm 32.","sound":"im32.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho 32."},
{"question":"I'm 6'2.","sound":"im6foot2.mp3","answer":"Eu meço 6'2 (1.87m)"},
{"question":"I'm a beginner.","sound":"imabeginner.mp3","answer":"Eu sou iniciante."},
{"question":"I'm a size 8.","sound":"imasize8.mp3","answer":"Meu tamanho é 8 (38)"},
{"question":"I'm a teacher.","sound":"imateacher.mp3","answer":"Eu sou professor/a."},
{"question":"I'm allergic to seafood.","sound":"imallergictoseafood.mp3","answer":"Eu sou alérgico a frutos do mar."},
{"question":"I'm American.","sound":"imamerican.mp3","answer":"Eu sou americano."},
{"question":"I'm an American.","sound":"imanamerican.mp3","answer":"Eu sou um americano."},
{"question":"I'm bored.","sound":"imbored.mp3","answer":"Eu estou entediado."},
{"question":"I'm cleaning my room.","sound":"imcleaningmyroom.mp3","answer":"Eu estou limpando meu quarto."},
{"question":"I'm cold.","sound":"imcold.mp3","answer":"Eu estou com frio."},
{"question":"I'm coming right now.","sound":"imcomingrightnow.mp3","answer":"Eu estou indo agora mesmo."},
{"question":"I'm coming to pick you up.","sound":"imcomingtopickyouup.mp3","answer":"Eu estou indo te buscar"},
{"question":"I'm fine, and you?","sound":"imfineandyou.mp3","answer":"Eu estou bem, e você?"},
{"question":"I'm from America.","sound":"imfromamerica.mp3","answer":"Eu sou dos Estados Unidos."},
{"question":"I'm full.","sound":"imfull.mp3","answer":"Eu estou satisfeito."},
{"question":"I'm getting ready to go out.","sound":"imgettingreadytogoout.mp3","answer":"Eu estou me aprontando pra sair."},
{"question":"I'm going home in four days.","sound":"imgoinghomeinfourdays.mp3","answer":"Eu vou pra casa em quatro dias."},
{"question":"I'm going to America next year.","sound":"imgoingtoamericanextyear.mp3","answer":"Eu vou para os Estados Unidos no ano que vem."},
{"question":"I'm going to bed.","sound":"imgoingtobed.mp3","answer":"Eu estou indo para a cama."},
{"question":"I'm going to go have dinner.","sound":"imgoingtogohavedinner.mp3","answer":"Eu estou indo jantar."},
{"question":"I'm going to leave.","sound":"imgoingtoleave.mp3","answer":"Eu vou sair."},
{"question":"I'm good, and you?","sound":"imgoodandyou.mp3","answer":"Eu estou bem, e você?"},
{"question":"I'm good.","sound":"imgood.mp3","answer":"Estou bem."},
{"question":"I'm happy.","sound":"imhappy.mp3","answer":"Estou feliz."},
{"question":"I'm here on business.","sound":"imhereonbusiness.mp3","answer":"Estou aqui a negócios."},
{"question":"I'm hungry.","sound":"imhungry.mp3","answer":"Estou com fome."},
{"question":"I'm just kidding.","sound":"imjustkidding.mp3","answer":"Estou só brincando."},
{"question":"I'm just looking.","sound":"imjustlooking.mp3","answer":"Estou só olhando (num Shopping)"},
{"question":"I'm leaving Tomorrow.","sound":"imleavingtomorrow.mp3","answer":"Estou partindo amanhã."},
{"question":"I'm looking for the post office.","sound":"imlookingforthepostoffice.mp3","answer":"Estou procurando o correio."},
{"question":"I'm lost","sound":"imlost.mp3","answer":"Estou perdido."},
{"question":"I'm married.","sound":"immarried.mp3","answer":"Sou casado."},
{"question":"I'm not afraid.","sound":"imnotafraid.mp3","answer":"Eu não estou com medo."},
{"question":"I'm not American.","sound":"imnotamerican.mp3","answer":"Eu não sou americano."},
{"question":"I'm not busy.","sound":"imnotbusy.mp3","answer":"Eu não estou ocupado."},
{"question":"I'm not going.","sound":"imnotgoing.mp3","answer":"Eu não vou."},
{"question":"I'm not married.","sound":"imnotmarried.mp3","answer":"Eu não sou casado."},
{"question":"I'm not ready yet.","sound":"imnotreadyyet.mp3","answer":"Eu ainda não estou pronto."},
{"question":"I'm not sure.","sound":"imnotsure.mp3","answer":"Eu não tenho certeza."},
{"question":"I'm ok.","sound":"imok.mp3","answer":"Estou OK."},
{"question":"I'm on hold. (phone)","sound":"imonhold.mp3","answer":"Eu estou aguardando (ao telefone)"},
{"question":"I'm ready.","sound":"imready.mp3","answer":"Estou pronto."},
{"question":"I'm self-employed.","sound":"imselfemployed.mp3","answer":"Eu tenho meu próprio negócio."},
{"question":"I'm sick.","sound":"imsick.mp3","answer":"Eu estou doente."},
{"question":"I'm single.","sound":"imsingle.mp3","answer":"Eu sou solteiro."},
{"question":"I'm sorry, we're sold out.","sound":"imsorryweresoldout.mp3","answer":"Lamento, está esgotado."},
{"question":"I'm sorry.","sound":"imsorry.mp3","answer":"Lamento/Sinto muito."},
{"question":"I'm thirsty.","sound":"imthirsty.mp3","answer":"Estou com sede."},
{"question":"I'm tired.","sound":"imtired.mp3","answer":"Estou cansado."},
{"question":"I'm very busy.","sound":"imverybusy.mp3","answer":"Estou muito ocupado."},
{"question":"I'm very busy. I don't have time now.","sound":"imverybusyidonthavetimenow.mp3","answer":"Estou muito ocupado. Não tenho tempo agora."},
{"question":"I'm very well, thank you.","sound":"imverywellthankyou.mp3","answer":"Eu estou muito bem, obrigado."},
{"question":"I'm waiting for you.","sound":"imwaitingforyou.mp3","answer":"Estou esperando você."},
{"question":"I'm worried too.","sound":"imworriedtoo.mp3","answer":"Estou preocupado também."},
{"question":"In 30 minutes.","sound":"in30minutes.mp3","answer":"Em 30 minutos."},
{"question":"Is anyone else coming?","sound":"isanyoneelsecoming.mp3","answer":"Alguém mais está vindo?"},
{"question":"Is everything ok?","sound":"iseverythingok.mp3","answer":"Está tudo OK?"},
{"question":"Is it close?","sound":"isitclose.mp3","answer":"Está fechado?"},
{"question":"Is it cold outside?","sound":"isitcoldoutside.mp3","answer":"Está frio lá fora?"},
{"question":"Is it far from here?","sound":"isitfarfromhere.mp3","answer":"É longe daqui?"},
{"question":"Is it hot?","sound":"isithot.mp3","answer":"Está quente?"},
{"question":"Is it nearby?","sound":"isitnearby.mp3","answer":"É próximo daqui?"},
{"question":"Is it possible?","sound":"isitpossible.mp3","answer":"É possível?"},
{"question":"Is it raining?","sound":"isitraining.mp3","answer":"Está chovendo?"},
{"question":"Is it ready?","sound":"isitready.mp3","answer":"Está pronto?"},
{"question":"Is it suppose to rain tomorrow?","sound":"isitsupposetoraintomorrow.mp3","answer":"Vai chover amanhã?"},
{"question":"Is John here?","sound":"isjohnhere.mp3","answer":"O John está aqui?"},
{"question":"Is John there please?","sound":"isjohnthereplease.mp3","answer":"O John está por favor? (ao telefone)"},
{"question":"Is Mr. Smith an American?","sound":"ismrsmithanamerican.mp3","answer":"O Sr. Smith é americano?"},
{"question":"Is that enough?","sound":"isthatenough.mp3","answer":"É o suficiente?"},
{"question":"Is that ok?","sound":"isthatok.mp3","answer":"Está OK?"},
{"question":"Is the bank far?","sound":"isthebankfar.mp3","answer":"O banco é longe?"},
{"question":"Is there a movie theater nearby?","sound":"isthereamovietheaternearby.mp3","answer":"Tem um cinema por aqui?"},
{"question":"Is there a nightclub in town?","sound":"isthereanightclubintown.mp3","answer":"Tem uma casa noturna/danceteria na cidade?"},
{"question":"Is there a restaurant in the hotel?","sound":"istherearestaurantinthehotel.mp3","answer":"Tem restaurante no hotel?"},
{"question":"Is there a store near here?","sound":"isthereastorenearhere.mp3","answer":"Tem uma loja por aqui?"},
{"question":"Is there air conditioning in the room?","sound":"isthereairconditioningintheroom.mp3","answer":"Tem ar condicionado neste quarto?"},
{"question":"Is there an English speaking guide?","sound":"isthereanenglishspeakingguide.mp3","answer":"Tem algum guia que fale inglês?"},
{"question":"Is there any mail for me?","sound":"isthereanymailforme.mp3","answer":"Tem alguma correspondência pra mim?"},
{"question":"Is there anything cheaper?","sound":"isthereanythingcheaper.mp3","answer":"Tem algo mais barato?"},
{"question":"Is this a safe area?","sound":"isthisasafearea.mp3","answer":"Esta área é segura?"},
{"question":"Is this Mr. Smith?","sound":"isthismrsmith.mp3","answer":"Este é o Sr. Smith?"},
{"question":"Is this pen yours?","sound":"isthispenyours.mp3","answer":"Esta caneta e tua?"},
{"question":"Is this the bus to New York?","sound":"isthisthebustony.mp3","answer":"Este é o ônibus para Nova Iorque?"},
{"question":"Is this your book?","sound":"isthisyourbook.mp3","answer":"Este livro é teu?"},
{"question":"Is your father home?","sound":"isyourfatherhome.mp3","answer":"O teu pai está em casa?"},
{"question":"Is your house like this one?","sound":"isyourhouselikethisone.mp3","answer":"A tua casa é como esta?"},
{"question":"Is your husband also from Boston?","sound":"isyourhusbandalsofromboston.mp3","answer":"O teu marido também é de Boston?"},
{"question":"Is your son here?","sound":"isyoursonhere.mp3","answer":"O teu filho está aqui?"},
{"question":"Isn't it?","sound":"isntit.mp3","answer":"Não é?"},
{"question":"It costs 20 dollars per hour.","sound":"itcosts20dollarsperhour.mp3","answer":"Custa 20 dólares por hora."},
{"question":"It depends on the weather.","sound":"itdependsontheweather.mp3","answer":"Depende do tempo."},
{"question":"It hurts here.","sound":"ithurtshere.mp3","answer":"Dói aqui."},
{"question":"It rained very hard today.","sound":"itrainedveryhardtoday.mp3","answer":"Choveu forte hoje."},
{"question":"It takes 2 hours by car.","sound":"ittakes2hoursbycar.mp3","answer":"Leva 2 horas de carro."},
{"question":"It will arrive shortly.","sound":"itwillarriveshortly.mp3","answer":"Vai chegar logo."},
{"question":"It'll be cold this evening.","sound":"itllbecoldthisevening.mp3","answer":"Vai fazer frio esta noite."},
{"question":"It's 11:30pm.","sound":"its1130.mp3","answer":"São 23h30."},
{"question":"It's 17 dollars.","sound":"its17dollars.mp3","answer":"São 17 dólares."},
{"question":"It's 6AM.","sound":"its6am.mp3","answer":"São 6 da manhã"},
{"question":"It's 8:45.","sound":"its845.mp3","answer":"São 8h45"},
{"question":"It's a quarter to 7.","sound":"itsaquarterto7.mp3","answer":"São quinze para as 7,"},
{"question":"It's August 25th.","sound":"itsaugust25th.mp3","answer":"Hoje é 25 de agosto."},
{"question":"It's delicious!","sound":"itsdelicious.mp3","answer":"Está delicioso."},
{"question":"It's far from here.","sound":"itsfarfromhere.mp3","answer":"É longe daqui."},
{"question":"It's going to be hot today.","sound":"itsgoingtobehottoday.mp3","answer":"Vai ser quente hoje."},
{"question":"It's going to snow today.","sound":"itsgoingtosnowtoday.mp3","answer":"Vai nevar hoje"},
{"question":"It's half past 11.","sound":"itshalfpast11.mp3","answer":"São onze e meia"},
{"question":"It's here.","sound":"itshere.mp3","answer":"É aqui."},
{"question":"It's is a quarter past nine.","sound":"itsaquarterpast9.mp3","answer":"São nove e quinze."},
{"question":"It's less than 5 dollars.","sound":"itslessthan5dollars.mp3","answer":"É menos de 5 dólares."},
{"question":"It's longer than 2 miles.","sound":"itslongerthan2miles.mp3","answer":"É mais longe que 2 milhas."},
{"question":"It's mine.","sound":"itsmine.mp3","answer":"É meu/minha."},
{"question":"It's more than 5 dollars.","sound":"itsmorethan5dollars.mp3","answer":"É mais que 5 dólares"},
{"question":"It's near the Supermarket.","sound":"itsnearthesupermarket.mp3","answer":"É perto do supermercado."},
{"question":"It's north of here.","sound":"itsnorthofhere.mp3","answer":"Fica ao norte daqui."},
{"question":"it's not suppose to rain today.","sound":"itsnotsupposetoraintoday.mp3","answer":"Não é pra chover hoje."},
{"question":"It's not too far.","sound":"itsnottoofar.mp3","answer":"Não é muito longe."},
{"question":"It's not very expensive.","sound":"itsnotveryexpensive.mp3","answer":"Não é muito caro."},
{"question":"It's ok.","sound":"itsok.mp3","answer":"Está OK."},
{"question":"It's on 7th street.","sound":"itson7thstreet.mp3","answer":"É na Sétima Rua."},
{"question":"It's over there.","sound":"itsoverthere.mp3","answer":"É ali pra cima."},
{"question":"It's raining.","sound":"itsraining.mp3","answer":"Está chovendo."},
{"question":"It's really hot.","sound":"itsreallyhot.mp3","answer":"Está bem calor."},
{"question":"It's shorter than 3 miles.","sound":"itsshorterthan3miles.mp3","answer":"É menos que 3 milhas."},
{"question":"It's suppose to rain tomorrow.","sound":"itssupposetoraintomorrow.mp3","answer":"É pra chover amanhã."},
{"question":"It's there.","sound":"itsthere.mp3","answer":"É ali."},
{"question":"It's too late.","sound":"itstoolate.mp3","answer":"É muito tarde/Tarde demais."},
{"question":"It's very cold today.","sound":"itsverycoldtoday.mp3","answer":"Está muito frio hoje."},
{"question":"It's very important.","sound":"itsveryimportant.mp3","answer":"É muito importante."},
{"question":"It's very windy.","sound":"itsverywindy.mp3","answer":"Está ventando bastante."},
{"question":"I've already seen it.","sound":"ivealreadyseenit.mp3","answer":"Eu já ví."},
{"question":"I've been here for two days.","sound":"ivebeenherefor2days.mp3","answer":"Eu estive aqui durante dois dias."},
{"question":"I've been there.","sound":"ivebeenthere.mp3","answer":"Eu já estive lá."},
{"question":"I've heard Texas is a beautiful place.","sound":"iveheardtexasisabeautifulplace.mp3","answer":"Eu ouví que o Texas é um belo lugar."},
{"question":"I've never done that.","sound":"iveneverdonethat.mp3","answer":"Eu nunca fiz isso."},
{"question":"I've never seen that before.","sound":"iveneverseenthatbefore.mp3","answer":"Eu nunca ví isso antes."},
{"question":"I've seen it.","sound":"iveseenit.mp3","answer":"Eu já vi."},
{"question":"I've worked there for five years.","sound":"iveworkedtherefor5years.mp3","answer":"Eu trabalhei lá por cinco anos."},
{"question":"John is going on vacation tomorrow.","sound":"johnisgoingonvacationtomorrow.mp3","answer":"John vai sair de férias amanhã."},
{"question":"June 3rd.","sound":"june3rd.mp3","answer":"3 de junho."},
{"question":"Just a little.","sound":"justalittle.mp3","answer":"Só um pouquinho."},
{"question":"Just a moment.","sound":"justamoment.mp3","answer":"Só um momento."},
{"question":"Let me check.","sound":"letmecheck.mp3","answer":"Deixa-me ver/checar."},
{"question":"Let me think about it.","sound":"letmethinkaboutit.mp3","answer":"Deixa-me pensar sobre isso."},
{"question":"Let's go have a look.","sound":"letsgohavealook.mp3","answer":"Vamos dar uma olhada."},
{"question":"Let's go.","sound":"letsgo.mp3","answer":"Vamos."},
{"question":"Let's meet in front of the hotel.","sound":"letsmeetinfrontofthehotel.mp3","answer":"Vamos nos encontrar em frente ao hotel."},
{"question":"Let's practice English.","sound":"letspracticeenglish.mp3","answer":"Vamos praticar inglês."},
{"question":"Let's share.","sound":"letsshare.mp3","answer":"Vamos dividir."},
{"question":"Male or female?","sound":"maleorfemale.mp3","answer":"Masculino ou feminino?"},
{"question":"May I speak to Mrs. Smith please?","sound":"mayispeaktomrssmithplease.mp3","answer":"Posso falar com a Sra. Smith por favor?"},
{"question":"Maybe.","sound":"maybe.mp3","answer":"Pode ser/Talvez."},
{"question":"More than 200 miles.","sound":"morethan200miles.mp3","answer":"Mais de 200 milhas"},
{"question":"More than that.","sound":"morethanthat.mp3","answer":"Mais do que isso."},
{"question":"My birthday is August 27th.","sound":"mybirthdayisaugust27.mp3","answer":"Meu aniversário é dia 27 de agosto."},
{"question":"My car isn't working.","sound":"mycarisntworking.mp3","answer":"Meu carro não está funcionando."},
{"question":"My car was hit by another car.","sound":"mycarwashitbyanothercar.mp3","answer":"Meu carro foi batido por um outro carro."},
{"question":"My cell phone doesn't have good reception.","sound":"mycellphonedoesnthavegoodreception.mp3","answer":"Meu celular não está com um bom sinal."},
{"question":"My cell phone doesn't work.","sound":"mycellphonedoesntwork.mp3","answer":"Meu celular não funciona."},
{"question":"My daughter is here.","sound":"mydaughterishere.mp3","answer":"Minha filha está aqui."},
{"question":"My father has been there.","sound":"myfatherhasbeenthere.mp3","answer":"Meu pai já esteve lá."},
{"question":"My father is a lawyer.","sound":"myfatherisalawyer.mp3","answer":"Meu pai é advogado."},
{"question":"My friend is American.","sound":"myfriendisamerican.mp3","answer":"Meu/Minha amigo/a é americano/a"},
{"question":"My grandmother passed away last year.","sound":"mygrandmotherpassedawaylastyear.mp3","answer":"Meu/Minha avô/avó morreu no ano passado."},
{"question":"My house is close to the bank.","sound":"myhouseisclosetothebank.mp3","answer":"Minha casa fica perto do banco."},
{"question":"My luggage is missing.","sound":"myluggageismissing.mp3","answer":"Minha bagagem está perdida."},
{"question":"My name is John Smith.","sound":"mynameisjohnsmith.mp3","answer":"Meu nome é John Smith."},
{"question":"My son studies computers.","sound":"mysonstudiescomputers.mp3","answer":"Me filho estuda computação."},
{"question":"My son.","sound":"myson.mp3","answer":"Meu filho."},
{"question":"My stomach hurts.","sound":"mystomachhurts.mp3","answer":"Meu estômago dói."},
{"question":"My throat is sore.","sound":"mythroatissore.mp3","answer":"Minha garganta está inflamada."},
{"question":"My watch has been stolen.","sound":"mywatchhasbeenstolen.mp3","answer":"Meu relógio foi roubado."},
{"question":"Near the bank.","sound":"nearthebank.mp3","answer":"Perto do banco."},
{"question":"Never mind.","sound":"nevermind.mp3","answer":"Não faz mal/Não importa."},
{"question":"Next time.","sound":"nexttime.mp3","answer":"Da próxima vez."},
{"question":"Nice to meet you","sound":"nicetomeetyou.mp3","answer":"Prazer em te conhecer."},
{"question":"No problem.","sound":"noproblem.mp3","answer":"Sem problemas."},
{"question":"No, I'm American.","sound":"noimamerican.mp3","answer":"Não, eu sou americano."},
{"question":"No, thank you.","sound":"nothankyou.mp3","answer":"Não, obrigado/a."},
{"question":"No, this is the first time.","sound":"nothisisthefirsttime.mp3","answer":"Não, esta é a primeira vez."},
{"question":"No.","sound":"no.mp3","answer":"Não."},
{"question":"Nobody is helping us.","sound":"nobodyishelpingus.mp3","answer":"Ninguém nos está ajudando."},
{"question":"Nobody is there right now.","sound":"nobodyisthererightnow.mp3","answer":"Não tem ninguém lá"},
{"question":"Nonsense.","sound":"nonsense.mp3","answer":"Bobagem/Que nada."},
{"question":"Not recently.","sound":"notrecently.mp3","answer":"Não recentemente."},
{"question":"Not yet.","sound":"notyet.mp3","answer":"Não ainda/Ainda não."},
{"question":"Nothing else.","sound":"nothingelse.mp3","answer":"Nada mais/Mais nada"},
{"question":"Now or later?","sound":"noworlater.mp3","answer":"Agora ou mais tarde?"},
{"question":"October 22nd.","sound":"october22.mp3","answer":"22 de outubro"},
{"question":"Of course.","sound":"ofcourse.mp3","answer":"Claro."},
{"question":"Okay.","sound":"ok.mp3","answer":"OK."},
{"question":"On the left.","sound":"ontheleft.mp3","answer":"À esquerda."},
{"question":"On the right.","sound":"ontheright.mp3","answer":"À direita."},
{"question":"On the second floor.","sound":"onthesecondfloor.mp3","answer":"No segundo andar."},
{"question":"One like that.","sound":"onelikethat.mp3","answer":"Um que nem aquele."},
{"question":"One ticket to New York please.","sound":"onetickettonyplease.mp3","answer":"Um bilhete para Nova Iorque por favor (passagem)"},
{"question":"One way or round trip?","sound":"onewayorroundtrip.mp3","answer":"Só ida ou ida e volta?"},
{"question":"Open the door.","sound":"openthedoor.mp3","answer":"Abra a porta."},
{"question":"Open the window.","sound":"openthewindow.mp3","answer":"Abra a janela."},
{"question":"Our children are in America.","sound":"ourchildrenareinamerica.mp3","answer":"Nossos filhos estão nos Estados Unidos."},
{"question":"Outside the hotel.","sound":"outsidethehotel.mp3","answer":"Fora do hotel."},
{"question":"Over here.","sound":"overhere.mp3","answer":"Por aqui/Cá"},
{"question":"Over there.","sound":"overthere.mp3","answer":"Por alí/Lá"},
{"question":"Pick up your clothes.","sound":"pickupyourclothes.mp3","answer":"Pegue tuas roupas."},
{"question":"Please call me.","sound":"pleasecallme.mp3","answer":"Por favor me ligue."},
{"question":"Please come in.","sound":"pleasecomein.mp3","answer":"Por favor, entre."},
{"question":"Please count this for me.","sound":"pleasecountthisforme.mp3","answer":"Por favor conte isto pra mim."},
{"question":"Please fill out this form.","sound":"pleasefilloutthisform.mp3","answer":"Por favor, preencha este formulário."},
{"question":"Please sit down.","sound":"pleasesitdown.mp3","answer":"Por favor, sente-se"},
{"question":"Please speak English.","sound":"pleasespeakenglish.mp3","answer":"Por favor, fale inglês."},
{"question":"Please speak more slowly.","sound":"pleasespeakmoreslowly.mp3","answer":"Por favor, fale mais devagar."},
{"question":"Please speak slower.","sound":"pleasespeakslower.mp3","answer":"Por favor, fale mais devagar."},
{"question":"Please take me to the airport.","sound":"pleasetakemetotheairport.mp3","answer":"Por favor me leve para o aeroporto."},
{"question":"Please take me to this address.","sound":"pleasetakemetothisaddress.mp3","answer":"Por favor me leve para este endereço"},
{"question":"Please take off your shoes.","sound":"pleasetakeoffyourshoes.mp3","answer":"Por favor tire teus sapatos."},
{"question":"Please tell her John called.","sound":"pleasetellherjohncalled.mp3","answer":"Por favor diga a ela que o John ligou."},
{"question":"Please tell me.","sound":"pleasetellme.mp3","answer":"Por favor me diga."},
{"question":"Please wait for me.","sound":"pleasewaitforme.mp3","answer":"Por favor espere por mim."},
{"question":"Please write it down.","sound":"pleasewriteitdown.mp3","answer":"Por favor escreva aqui."},
{"question":"Please.","sound":"please.mp3","answer":"Por favor."},
{"question":"Really?","sound":"really.mp3","answer":"Mesmo?/De verdade?"},
{"question":"Right here.","sound":"righthere.mp3","answer":"Bem aqui."},
{"question":"Right there.","sound":"rightthere.mp3","answer":"Bem alí."},
{"question":"See you later.","sound":"seeyoulater.mp3","answer":"Te vejo mais tarde."},
{"question":"See you tomorrow.","sound":"seeyoutomorrow.mp3","answer":"Te vejo amanhã."},
{"question":"See you tonight.","sound":"seeyoutonight.mp3","answer":"Te vejo à noite."},
{"question":"She wants to know when you're coming.","sound":"shewantstoknowwhenyourcoming.mp3","answer":"Ela quer saber quando você vem."},
{"question":"She's an expert.","sound":"shesanexpert.mp3","answer":"Ela é uma especialista/perita."},
{"question":"She's going with me tomorrow.","sound":"shesgoingwithmetomorrow.mp3","answer":"Ela vai comigo amanhã"},
{"question":"She's older than me.","sound":"shesolderthanme.mp3","answer":"Ela é mais velha que eu."},
{"question":"She's pretty.","sound":"shespretty.mp3","answer":"Ela é bonita."},
{"question":"Should I wait?","sound":"shouldiwait.mp3","answer":"Eu deveria esperar?"},
{"question":"Some books.","sound":"somebooks.mp3","answer":"Alguns livros."},
{"question":"Someone does that for me.","sound":"someonedoesthatforme.mp3","answer":"Alguém faz isso pra mim."},
{"question":"Someone is coming.","sound":"someoneiscoming.mp3","answer":"Alguém está vindo."},
{"question":"Sometimes I go to sleep at 11PM, sometimes at 11:30PM.","sound":"sometimesigotosleepat11sometimesat1130.mp3","answer":"Às vezes eu vou dormir às 23h, algumas vezes às 23h30."},
{"question":"Sorry to bother you.","sound":"sorrytobotheryou.mp3","answer":"Me perdoe te importunar."},
{"question":"Sorry, I didn't hear clearly.","sound":"sorryididnthearclearly.mp3","answer":"Desculpe, eu não ouvi claramente."},
{"question":"Sorry, I don't have a pencil.","sound":"sorryidonthaveapencil.mp3","answer":"Desculpe, eu nao tenho um lápis."},
{"question":"Sorry, I think I have the wrong number.","sound":"sorryithinkihavethewrongnumber.mp3","answer":"Desculpe, eu acho que eu tenho um número errado."},
{"question":"Sorry, we don't accept credit cards.","sound":"sorrywedontacceptcreditcards.mp3","answer":"Desculpe, nós não aceitamos cartão de crédito."},
{"question":"Sorry, we don't have any vacancies.","sound":"sorrywedonthaveanyvaccancies.mp3","answer":"Desculpe, nós não temos vagas."},
{"question":"Sorry, we don't have any.","sound":"sorrywedonthaveany.mp3","answer":"Desculpe, nós não temos nenhum/a"},
{"question":"Sorry, we only accept Cash.","sound":"sorryweonlyacceptcash.mp3","answer":"Desculpe, nós só aceitamos em dinheiro."},
{"question":"Start the car.","sound":"startthecar.mp3","answer":"Ligue o carro."},
{"question":"Stop!","sound":"stop.mp3","answer":"Pare!"},
{"question":"Take a chance.","sound":"takeachance.mp3","answer":"Arrisque."},
{"question":"Take it outside.","sound":"takeitoutside.mp3","answer":"Leve pra fora."},
{"question":"Take me downtown.","sound":"takemedowntown.mp3","answer":"Leve-me para o centro da cidade"},
{"question":"Take me to the Marriott Hotel.","sound":"takemetothemarriotthotel.mp3","answer":"Leve-me para o Hotel Marriott"},
{"question":"Take this medicine.","sound":"takethismedicine.mp3","answer":"Tome este remédio."},
{"question":"Tell him that I need to talk to him.","sound":"tellhimthatineedtotalktohim.mp3","answer":"Diga a ele que eu preciso falar com ele."},
{"question":"Tell me.","sound":"tellme.mp3","answer":"Diga-me."},
{"question":"Thank you miss.","sound":"thankyoumiss.mp3","answer":"Obrigado/a senhorita."},
{"question":"Thank you sir.","sound":"thankyousir.mp3","answer":"Obrigado/a senhor."},
{"question":"Thank you very much.","sound":"thankyouverymuch.mp3","answer":"Muito obrigado/a."},
{"question":"Thank you.","sound":"thankyou.mp3","answer":"Obrigado/a."},
{"question":"Thanks for everything.","sound":"thanksforeverything.mp3","answer":"Obrigado/a por tudo."},
{"question":"Thanks for your help.","sound":"thanksforyourhelp.mp3","answer":"Obrigado/a pela tua ajuda"},
{"question":"Thanks.","sound":"thanks.mp3","answer":"Obrigado/a. - Grato/a"},
{"question":"That car is similar to my car.","sound":"thatcarissimilartomycar.mp3","answer":"Aquele carro parece o meu."},
{"question":"That car over there is mine.","sound":"thatcaroverthereismine.mp3","answer":"Aquele carro ali é meu."},
{"question":"That looks great.","sound":"thatlooksgreat.mp3","answer":"Está ótimo (aparência)"},
{"question":"That looks old.","sound":"thatlooksold.mp3","answer":"Parece velho."},
{"question":"That means friend.","sound":"thatmeansfriend.mp3","answer":"Isso significa amigo."},
{"question":"That restaurant is not expensive.","sound":"thatrestaurantisnotexpensive.mp3","answer":"Aquele restaurante não é caro."},
{"question":"That smells bad.","sound":"thatsmellsbad.mp3","answer":"Isso cheira ruim."},
{"question":"That way.","sound":"thatway.mp3","answer":"Por alí (naquela direção)"},
{"question":"That's a good school.","sound":"thatsagoodschool.mp3","answer":"Aquela é uma boa escola."},
{"question":"That's alright.","sound":"thatsalright.mp3","answer":"Tudo bem."},
{"question":"That's enough.","sound":"thatsenough.mp3","answer":"Chega (é o suficiente)"},
{"question":"That's fair.","sound":"thatsfair.mp3","answer":"É justo."},
{"question":"That's fine.","sound":"thatsfine.mp3","answer":"Está bom."},
{"question":"That's her book.","sound":"thatsherbook.mp3","answer":"Esse é o livro dela."},
{"question":"That's it.","sound":"thatsit.mp3","answer":"É isso."},
{"question":"That's not enough.","sound":"thatsnotenough.mp3","answer":"Isso não é o bastante/suficiente."},
{"question":"That's not fair.","sound":"thatsnotfair.mp3","answer":"Isso não é justo"},
{"question":"That's not right.","sound":"thatsnotright.mp3","answer":"Isso não está certo."},
{"question":"That's right.","sound":"thatsright.mp3","answer":"Está certo."},
{"question":"That's too bad.","sound":"thatstoobad.mp3","answer":"Isso é muito mal/ruim."},
{"question":"That's too expensive.","sound":"thatstooexpensive.mp3","answer":"Isso é muito caro."},
{"question":"That's too late.","sound":"thatstoolate.mp3","answer":"Isso é tarde demais."},
{"question":"That's too many.","sound":"thatstoomany.mp3","answer":"Isso é muito (quantidade)"},
{"question":"That's too much.","sound":"thatstoomuch.mp3","answer":"Isso é muito (quantidade)"},
{"question":"That's wrong.","sound":"thatswrong.mp3","answer":"Está errado"},
{"question":"The accident happened at the intersection.","sound":"theaccidenthappenedattheintersection.mp3","answer":"O acidente aconteceu no cruzamento."},
{"question":"The big one or the small one?","sound":"thebigoneorthesmallone.mp3","answer":"O grande ou o pequeno?"},
{"question":"The book is behind the table.","sound":"thebookisbehinedthetable.mp3","answer":"O livro está atrás da mesa."},
{"question":"The book is in front of the table.","sound":"thebookisinfrontofthetable.mp3","answer":"O livro está na frente da mesa."},
{"question":"The book is near the table.","sound":"thebookisnearthetable.mp3","answer":"O livro está perto da mesa."},
{"question":"The book is next to the table.","sound":"thebookisnexttothetable.mp3","answer":"O livro está ao lado da mesa."},
{"question":"The book is on the table.","sound":"thebookisonthetable.mp3","answer":"O livro está sobre a mesa."},
{"question":"The book is on top of the table.","sound":"thebookisontopofthetable.mp3","answer":"O livro está no topo da mesa."},
{"question":"The book is under the table.","sound":"thebookisunderthetable.mp3","answer":"O livro está debaixo da mesa."},
{"question":"The books are expensive.","sound":"thebooksareexpensive.mp3","answer":"Os livros são caros."},
{"question":"The car is fixed.","sound":"thecarisfixed.mp3","answer":"O carro está consertado."},
{"question":"The cars are American.","sound":"thecarsareamerican.mp3","answer":"Os carros são americanos."},
{"question":"The food was delicious.","sound":"thefoodwasdelicious.mp3","answer":"A comida estava deliciosa."},
{"question":"The plane departs at 5:30P.","sound":"theplanedepartsat530.mp3","answer":"O avião parte às 17h30."},
{"question":"The roads are slippery.","sound":"theroadsareslippery.mp3","answer":"As estradas estão escorregadias."},
{"question":"The TV is broken.","sound":"thetvisbroken.mp3","answer":"A TV está quebrada."},
{"question":"The whole day.","sound":"thewholeday.mp3","answer":"O dia todo."},
{"question":"There are many people here.","sound":"therearemanypeoplehere.mp3","answer":"Tem muita gente aqui."},
{"question":"There are some apples in the refrigerator.","sound":"therearesomeapplesintherefrigerator.mp3","answer":"Tem algumas maçãs na geladeira."},
{"question":"There are some books on the table.","sound":"therearesomebooksonthetable.mp3","answer":"Tem alguns livros na mesa."},
{"question":"There has been a car accident.","sound":"therehasbeenacaraccident.mp3","answer":"Houve um acidente de carro."},
{"question":"There's a book under the table.","sound":"theresabookunderthetable.mp3","answer":"Tem um livro sob a mesa."},
{"question":"There's a restaurant near here.","sound":"theresarestaurantnearhere.mp3","answer":"Tem um restaurante aqui perto."},
{"question":"There's a restaurant over there, but I don't think it's very good.","sound":"theresarestaurantovertherebutidontthinkitsverygood.mp3","answer":"Tem um restaurante alí mas eu não acho que seja muito bom."},
{"question":"There's plenty of time.","sound":"theresplentyoftime.mp3","answer":"Tem muito tempo."},
{"question":"These books are ours.","sound":"thesebooksareours.mp3","answer":"Esses livros são nossos."},
{"question":"They arrived yesterday.","sound":"theyarrivedyesterday.mp3","answer":"Eles chegaram ontem."},
{"question":"They charge 26 dollars per day.","sound":"theycharge26dollarsperday.mp3","answer":"Eles cobram 26 dólares por dia."},
{"question":"They haven't met her yet.","sound":"theyhaventmetheryet.mp3","answer":"Eles ainda não a encontraram."},
{"question":"They'll be right back.","sound":"theyllberightback.mp3","answer":"Eles voltam logo."},
{"question":"They're planning to come next year.","sound":"theyreplanningtocomenextyear.mp3","answer":"Eles planejam vir no ano que vem."},
{"question":"They're the same.","sound":"theyrethesame.mp3","answer":"Eles são os mesmos."},
{"question":"They're very busy.","sound":"theyreverybusy.mp3","answer":"Eles estão bem ocupados."},
{"question":"They're waiting for us.","sound":"theyrewaitingforus.mp3","answer":"Eles estão nos esperando."},
{"question":"This doesn't work.","sound":"thisdoesntwork.mp3","answer":"Isto não funciona."},
{"question":"This house is very big.","sound":"thishouseisverybig.mp3","answer":"Esta casa é bem grande."},
{"question":"This is Mrs. Smith.","sound":"thisismrssmith.mp3","answer":"Esta é a Sra. Smith."},
{"question":"This is my mother.","sound":"thisismymother.mp3","answer":"Esta é a minha mãe."},
{"question":"This is the first time I've been here.","sound":"thisisthefirsttimeivebeenhere.mp3","answer":"Esta é a primeira vez que eu venho aqui."},
{"question":"This is very difficult.","sound":"thisisverydifficult.mp3","answer":"Isto é muito difícil."},
{"question":"This is very important.","sound":"thisisveryimportant.mp3","answer":"Isto é muito importante."},
{"question":"This room is a mess.","sound":"thisroomisamess.mp3","answer":"Este quarto está uma bagunça."},
{"question":"Those men are speaking English.","sound":"thosemenarespeakingenglish.mp3","answer":"Aqueles homens estão falando inglês."},
{"question":"Try it on.","sound":"tryiton.mp3","answer":"Prove-o."},
{"question":"Try it.","sound":"tryit.mp3","answer":"Prove."},
{"question":"Try to say it.","sound":"trytosayit.mp3","answer":"Tente dizê-lo."},
{"question":"Turn around.","sound":"turnaround.mp3","answer":"Vire-se"},
{"question":"Turn left.","sound":"turnleft.mp3","answer":"Vire a esquerda"},
{"question":"Turn right.","sound":"turnright.mp3","answer":"Vire a direita"},
{"question":"Very good, thanks.","sound":"verygoodthanks.mp3","answer":"Muito bem, obrigado/a."},
{"question":"Waiter!","sound":"waiter.mp3","answer":"Garçon!"},
{"question":"Waitress!","sound":"waitress.mp3","answer":"Garçonete!"},
{"question":"We can eat Italian or Chinese food.","sound":"wecaneatitalianorchinesefood.mp3","answer":"Nós podemos comer comida italiana ou chinesa."},
{"question":"We have two boys and one girl.","sound":"wehavetwoboysandonegirl.mp3","answer":"Nós temos dois garotos e uma garota."},
{"question":"We like it very much.","sound":"welikeitverymuch.mp3","answer":"Nós gostamos muito."},
{"question":"We'll have two glasses of water please.","sound":"wellhavetwoglassesofwaterplease.mp3","answer":"Nós queremos dois copos com água por favor."},
{"question":"We're from California.","sound":"werefromcalifornia.mp3","answer":"Nós somos da Califórnia."},
{"question":"We're late.","sound":"werelate.mp3","answer":"Nós estamos atrasados."},
{"question":"Were there any problems?","sound":"werethereanyproblems.mp3","answer":"Houve algum problema?"},
{"question":"Were you at the library last night?","sound":"wereyouatthelibrarylastnight.mp3","answer":"Você estava na biblioteca ontem à noite?"},
{"question":"What are you doing?","sound":"whatareyoudoing.mp3","answer":"O que você está fazendo?"},
{"question":"What are you going to do tonight?","sound":"whatareyougoingtodotonight.mp3","answer":"O que você vai fazer hoje à noite?"},
{"question":"What are you going to have?","sound":"whatareyougoingtohave.mp3","answer":"O que você vai quere?"},
{"question":"What are you thinking about?","sound":"whatareyouthinkingabout.mp3","answer":"No que você está pensando?"},
{"question":"What are you two talking about?","sound":"whatareyoutwotalkingabout.mp3","answer":"Sobre o que vocês dois estão falando?"},
{"question":"What are your hobbies?","sound":"whatareyourhobbies.mp3","answer":"Quais são os teus passsatempos?"},
{"question":"What can I do for you?","sound":"whatcanidoforyou.mp3","answer":"O que posso fazer por você?"},
{"question":"What color is that car?","sound":"whatcoloristhatcar.mp3","answer":"De que cor é aquele carro?"},
{"question":"What day are they coming over?","sound":"whatdayaretheycomingover.mp3","answer":"Em qual dia eles vem?"},
{"question":"What day of the week is it?","sound":"whatdayoftheweekisit.mp3","answer":"Que dia da semana é hoje?"},
{"question":"What did you do last night?","sound":"whatdidyoudolastnight.mp3","answer":"O que você fez ontem à noite?"},
{"question":"What did you do yesterday?","sound":"whatdidyoudoyesterday.mp3","answer":"O que você fez ontem?"},
{"question":"What did you think?","sound":"whatdidyouthink.mp3","answer":"O que você achou?"},
{"question":"What do people usually do in the summer in Los Angeles?","sound":"whatdopeopleusuallydointhesummerinlosangeles.mp3","answer":"O que as pessoas geralmente fazerm no verão em Los Angeles?"},
{"question":"What do they study?","sound":"whatdotheystudy.mp3","answer":"O que eles estudam?"},
{"question":"What do you do for work?","sound":"whatdoyoudoforwork.mp3","answer":"No que você trabalha?"},
{"question":"What do you have?","sound":"whatdoyouhave.mp3","answer":"O que você tem?"},
{"question":"What do you recommend?","sound":"whatdoyourecommend.mp3","answer":"O que você recomenda?"},
{"question":"What do you study?","sound":"whatdoyoustudy.mp3","answer":"O que você estuda?"},
{"question":"What do you think of these shoes?","sound":"whatdoyouthinkoftheseshoes.mp3","answer":"O que você acha destes sapatos?"},
{"question":"What do you think?","sound":"whatdoyouthink.mp3","answer":"O que você acha?"},
{"question":"What do you want to buy?","sound":"whatdoyouwanttobuy.mp3","answer":"O que você quer comprar?"},
{"question":"What do you want to do?","sound":"whatdoyouwanttodo.mp3","answer":"O que você quer fazer?"},
{"question":"What do your parents do for work?","sound":"whatdoyourparentsdoforwork.mp3","answer":"No que teus pais trabalham?"},
{"question":"What does he do for work?","sound":"whatdoeshedoforwork.mp3","answer":"No que ele trabalha?"},
{"question":"What does this mean?","sound":"whatdoesthismean.mp3","answer":"O que isso significa?"},
{"question":"What does this say?","sound":"whatdoesthissay.mp3","answer":"O que isso diz?"},
{"question":"What does this word mean?","sound":"whatdoesthiswordmean.mp3","answer":"O que significa esta palavra?"},
{"question":"What does your father do for work?","sound":"whatdoesyourfatherdoforwork.mp3","answer":"No que teu pai trabalha?"},
{"question":"What happened?","sound":"whathappened.mp3","answer":"O que aconteceu?"},
{"question":"What is it?","sound":"whatisit.mp3","answer":"O que é?"},
{"question":"What is that?","sound":"whatisthat.mp3","answer":"O que é isso?"},
{"question":"What is the area code?","sound":"whatistheareacode.mp3","answer":"Qual é o DDD (Código de Área)"},
{"question":"What is today's date?","sound":"whatistodaysdate.mp3","answer":"Que dia é hoje?"},
{"question":"What kind of music do you like?","sound":"whatkindofmusicdoyoulike.mp3","answer":"Que tipo de música voce gosta?"},
{"question":"What school did you go to?","sound":"whatschooldidyougoto.mp3","answer":"Em que escola você foi?"},
{"question":"What should I wear?","sound":"whatshouldiwear.mp3","answer":"O que eu deveria vestir?"},
{"question":"What size?","sound":"whatsize.mp3","answer":"Que tamanho?"},
{"question":"What time are they arriving?","sound":"whattimearetheyarriving.mp3","answer":"A que horas eles chegam?"},
{"question":"What time are you going to the bus station?","sound":"whattimeareyougoingtothebusstation.mp3","answer":"A que horas você vai a rodoviária?"},
{"question":"What time did you get up?","sound":"whattimedidyougetup.mp3","answer":"A que horas você se levanta?"},
{"question":"What time did you go to sleep?","sound":"whattimedidyougotosleep.mp3","answer":"A que horas você foi dormir?"},
{"question":"What time did you wake up?","sound":"whattimedidyouwakeup.mp3","answer":"A que horas você acordou?"},
{"question":"What time do you go to work everyday?","sound":"whattimedoyougotoworkeveryday.mp3","answer":"A que horas você vai para o trabalho todos os dias?"},
{"question":"What time do you think you'll arrive?","sound":"whattimedoyouthinkyoullarrive.mp3","answer":"Que horas você acha que vai chegar?"},
{"question":"What time does it start?","sound":"whattimedoesitstart.mp3","answer":"A que horas começa?"},
{"question":"What time does the movie start?","sound":"whattimedoesthemoviestart.mp3","answer":"A que horas o filme começa?"},
{"question":"What time does the store open?","sound":"whattimedoesthestoreopen.mp3","answer":"A que horas a loja abre?"},
{"question":"What time is check out?","sound":"whattimeischeckout.mp3","answer":"A que horas é a saída do hotel?"},
{"question":"What time is it?","sound":"whattimeisit.mp3","answer":"Que horas são?"},
{"question":"What will the weather be like tomorrow?","sound":"whatwilltheweatherbeliketomorrow.mp3","answer":"Como vai estar o tempo amanhã?"},
{"question":"What would you like to drink?","sound":"whatwouldyouliketodrink.mp3","answer":"O que você gostaria de beber?"},
{"question":"What would you like to eat?","sound":"whatwouldyouliketoeat.mp3","answer":"O que você gostaria de comer?"},
{"question":"What's in it?","sound":"whatsinit.mp3","answer":"O que tem nisso?"},
{"question":"What's the address?","sound":"whatstheaddress.mp3","answer":"Qual é o endereço?"},
{"question":"What's the charge per night? (Hotel)","sound":"whatsthechargepernight.mp3","answer":"Qual é a diária? (hotel)"},
{"question":"What's the date?","sound":"whatsthedate.mp3","answer":"Qual data?/Que dia?"},
{"question":"What's the exchange rate for dollars?","sound":"whatstheexcahngeratefordollars.mp3","answer":"Qual é a taxa de conversão para o dólar?"},
{"question":"What's the exchange rate?","sound":"whatstheexchangerate.mp3","answer":"Qual é a taxa de conversão?"},
{"question":"What's the matter?","sound":"whatsthematter.mp3","answer":"Qual é o problema?"},
{"question":"What's the name of the company you work for?","sound":"whatsthenameofthecompanyyouworkfor.mp3","answer":"Qual o nome da empresa para a qual você trabalha?"},
{"question":"What's the phone number?","sound":"whatsthephonenumber.mp3","answer":"Qual é o número do telefone?"},
{"question":"What's the room rate?","sound":"whatstheroomrate.mp3","answer":"Qual é a diária? (hotel)"},
{"question":"What's the temperature?","sound":"whatsthetemerature.mp3","answer":"Qual é a temperatura?"},
{"question":"What's this?","sound":"whatsthis.mp3","answer":"O que é isto?"},
{"question":"What's today's date?","sound":"whatstodaysdate.mp3","answer":"Que dia é hoje?"},
{"question":"What's up?","sound":"whatsup.mp3","answer":"O que se passa?/O que está acontecendo?"},
{"question":"What's wrong?","sound":"whatswrong.mp3","answer":"O que está errado?"},
{"question":"What's your address?","sound":"whatsyouraddress.mp3","answer":"Qual é o teu endereço?"},
{"question":"What's your email address?","sound":"whatsyouremailaddress.mp3","answer":"Qual é o teu endereço eletrônico? (email)"},
{"question":"What's your favorite food?","sound":"whatsyourfavoriatefood.mp3","answer":"Qual é a tua comida favorita?"},
{"question":"What's your favorite movie?","sound":"whatsyourfavoriatemovie.mp3","answer":"Qual é o teu filme favorito?"},
{"question":"What's your last name?","sound":"whatsyourlastname.mp3","answer":"Qual é o teu sobrenome?"},
{"question":"What's your name?","sound":"whatsyourname.mp3","answer":"Qual é o teu nome?"},
{"question":"What's your religion?","sound":"whatsyourreligion.mp3","answer":"Qual é a tua religião?"},
{"question":"When are they coming?","sound":"whenaretheycoming.mp3","answer":"Quado eles estão vindo?"},
{"question":"When are you coming back?","sound":"whenareyoucomingback.mp3","answer":"Quando você volta?"},
{"question":"When are you going to pick up your friend?","sound":"whenareyougoingtopickupyourfriend.mp3","answer":"Quando você vai buscar teu/tua amigo/a?"},
{"question":"When are you leaving?","sound":"whenareyouleaving.mp3","answer":"Quando você parte?"},
{"question":"When are you moving?","sound":"whenareyoumoving.mp3","answer":"Quando você se muda?"},
{"question":"When did this happen?","sound":"whendidthishappen.mp3","answer":"Quando isso aconteceu?"},
{"question":"When did you arrive in Boston?","sound":"whendidyouarriveinboston.mp3","answer":"Quando você chegou em Boston?"},
{"question":"When do we arrive?","sound":"whendowearrive.mp3","answer":"Quando nós chegamos?"},
{"question":"When do we leave?","sound":"whendoweleave.mp3","answer":"Quando nós partimos?"},
{"question":"When do you arrive in the U.S.?","sound":"whendoyouarriveintheus.mp3","answer":"Quando você chega nos EUA?"},
{"question":"When do you get off work?","sound":"whendoyougetoffwork.mp3","answer":"Quando você sai do trabalho?"},
{"question":"When do you start work?","sound":"whendoyoustartwork.mp3","answer":"Quando você começa a trabalhar?"},
{"question":"When does he arrive?","sound":"whendoeshearrive.mp3","answer":"Quando ele chega?"},
{"question":"When does it arrive?","sound":"whendoesitarrive.mp3","answer":"Quando chega?"},
{"question":"When does the bank open?","sound":"whendoesthebankopen.mp3","answer":"Quando abre o banco?"},
{"question":"When does the bus leave?","sound":"whendoesthebusleave.mp3","answer":"Quando parte o ônibus?"},
{"question":"When does the plane arrive?","sound":"whendoestheplanearrive.mp3","answer":"Quando chega o avião?"},
{"question":"When I went to the store, they didn't have any apples.","sound":"wheniwenttothestoretheydidnthaveanyapples.mp3","answer":"Quando eu fui à loja ele não tinham nenhuma maçã."},
{"question":"When is the next bus to Philadelphia?","sound":"whenisthenextbutophiladelphia.mp3","answer":"Quando é o próximo ônibus para a Filadélfia?"},
{"question":"When is your birthday?","sound":"whenisyourbirthday.mp3","answer":"Quando é o teu aniversário?"},
{"question":"When was the last time you talked to your mother?","sound":"whenwasthelasttimeyoutalkedtoyourmother.mp3","answer":"Quando foi a última vez que você falou com tua mãe?"},
{"question":"When will he be back?","sound":"whenwillhebeback.mp3","answer":"Quando ele volta?"},
{"question":"When will it be ready?","sound":"whenwillitbeready.mp3","answer":"Quando ficará pronto?"},
{"question":"When would you like to meet?","sound":"whenwouldyouliketomeet.mp3","answer":"Quando você quer se encontrar?"},
{"question":"Where are the t-shirts?","sound":"wherearethetshirts.mp3","answer":"Onde estão as camisetas?"},
{"question":"Where are you from?","sound":"whereareyoufrom.mp3","answer":"De onde você é?"},
{"question":"Where are you going to go?","sound":"whereareyougoingtogo.mp3","answer":"Onde você está indo?"},
{"question":"Where are you going?","sound":"whereareyougoing.mp3","answer":"Onde você está indo?"},
{"question":"Where are you?","sound":"whereareyou.mp3","answer":"Onde estã você?"},
{"question":"Where can I buy tickets?","sound":"wherecanibuytickets.mp3","answer":"Onde posso comprar os ingressos?"},
{"question":"Where can I exchange U.S. dollars?","sound":"wherecaniexchangeusdollars.mp3","answer":"Onde posso trocar dólares?"},
{"question":"Where can I find a hospital?","sound":"wherecanifindahospital.mp3","answer":"Onde posso achar um hospital?"},
{"question":"Where can I mail this?","sound":"wherecanimailthis.mp3","answer":"Onde posso postar isto?"},
{"question":"Where can I rent a car?","sound":"wherecanirentacar.mp3","answer":"Onde posso alugar um carro?"},
{"question":"Where did it happen?","sound":"wheredidithappen.mp3","answer":"Quando aconteceu?"},
{"question":"Where did you go?","sound":"wheredidyougo.mp3","answer":"Onde você foi?"},
{"question":"Where did you learn English?","sound":"wheredidyoulearnenglish.mp3","answer":"Onde você aprendeu inglês?"},
{"question":"Where did you learn it?","sound":"wheredidyoulearnit.mp3","answer":"Onde você aprendeu?"},
{"question":"Where did you put it?","sound":"wheredidyouputit.mp3","answer":"Onde você colocou?"},
{"question":"Where did you work before you worked here?","sound":"wheredidyouworkbeforeyouworkedhere.mp3","answer":"Onde você trabalhou antes daqui?"},
{"question":"Where do you live?","sound":"wheredoyoulive.mp3","answer":"Onde você mora?"},
{"question":"Where do you want to go?","sound":"wheredoyouwanttogo.mp3","answer":"Onde você quer ir?"},
{"question":"Where do you work?","sound":"wheredoyouwork.mp3","answer":"Onde você trabalha?"},
{"question":"Where does it hurt?","sound":"wheredoesithurt.mp3","answer":"Onde doi?"},
{"question":"Where does your wife work?","sound":"wheredoesyourwifework.mp3","answer":"Onde tua esposa trabalha?"},
{"question":"Where is an ATM?","sound":"whereisanatm.mp3","answer":"Onde tem um caixa eletrônico?"},
{"question":"Where is he from?","sound":"whereishefrom.mp3","answer":"De onde ele é?"},
{"question":"Where is he?","sound":"whereishe.mp3","answer":"Onde ele está?"},
{"question":"Where is it?","sound":"whereisit.mp3","answer":"Onde está?"},
{"question":"Where is Main Street?","sound":"whereismainstreet.mp3","answer":"Onde fica a Rua Principal?"},
{"question":"Where is my shirt?","sound":"whereismyshirt.mp3","answer":"Onde está minha camisa?"},
{"question":"Where is she from?","sound":"whereisshefrom.mp3","answer":"De onde ela é?"},
{"question":"Where is the airport?","sound":"whereistheairport.mp3","answer":"Onde fica o aerporto?"},
{"question":"Where is the bathroom?","sound":"whereisthebathroom.mp3","answer":"Onde fica o banheiro?"},
{"question":"Where is the bus station?","sound":"whereisthebusstation.mp3","answer":"Onde fica a rodoviária?"},
{"question":"Where is there a doctor who speaks English?","sound":"whereisthereadoctorwhospeaksenglish.mp3","answer":"Onde tem um médico que fale inglês?"},
{"question":"Where is there an ATM?","sound":"whereisthereanatm.mp3","answer":"Onde tem um caixa eletrônico?"},
{"question":"Where were you?","sound":"wherewereyou.mp3","answer":"Onde você estava?"},
{"question":"Where would you like to go?","sound":"wherewouldyouliketogo.mp3","answer":"Onde você gostaria de ir?"},
{"question":"Where would you like to meet?","sound":"wherewouldyouliketomeet.mp3","answer":"Onde você gostaria de se encontrar?"},
{"question":"Where's the closest restaurant?","sound":"wherestheclosestrestaurant.mp3","answer":"Onde fica o restaurante mais próximo?"},
{"question":"Where's the mail box?","sound":"wheresthemailbox.mp3","answer":"Onde tem uma caixa de correio?"},
{"question":"Where's the nearest hospital?","sound":"wheresthenearesthospital.mp3","answer":"Onde fica o hospital mais próximo?"},
{"question":"Where's the pharmacy?","sound":"wheresthepharmacy.mp3","answer":"Onde tem uma farmácia?"},
{"question":"Where's the post office?","sound":"wheresthepostoffice.mp3","answer":"Onde fica o correio?"},
{"question":"Which is better, the spaghetti or chicken salad?","sound":"whichisbetterthespaghettiorchickensalad.mp3","answer":"Qual é melhor o espaguete ou a salada de frango?"},
{"question":"Which is better?","sound":"whichisbetter.mp3","answer":"Qual é melhor?"},
{"question":"Which is the best?","sound":"whichisthebest.mp3","answer":"Qual é o/a melhor?"},
{"question":"Which one do you want?","sound":"whichonedoyouwant.mp3","answer":"Qual você quer?"},
{"question":"Which one is better?","sound":"whichoneisbetter.mp3","answer":"Quail deles/delas é melhor?"},
{"question":"Which one is cheaper?","sound":"whichoneischeaper.mp3","answer":"Qual é mais barato?"},
{"question":"Which one is the best?","sound":"whichoneisthebest.mp3","answer":"Qual é o/a melhor?"},
{"question":"Which one?","sound":"whichone.mp3","answer":"Qual deles?"},
{"question":"Which road should I take?","sound":"whichroadshoulditake.mp3","answer":"Que estrada eu deveria pegar?"},
{"question":"Which school does he go to?","sound":"whichschooldoeshegoto.mp3","answer":"Em qual escola ele vai?"},
{"question":"Who are they?","sound":"whoarethey.mp3","answer":"Quem são eles?"},
{"question":"Who are you looking for?","sound":"whoareyoulookingfor.mp3","answer":"Quem você está procurando?"},
{"question":"Who are you?","sound":"whoareyou.mp3","answer":"Quem é você?"},
{"question":"Who is it?","sound":"whoisit.mp3","answer":"Quem fala? (perguntando quem está no telefone)"},
{"question":"Who is that?","sound":"whoisthat.mp3","answer":"Quem é?"},
{"question":"Who sent this letter?","sound":"whosentthisletter.mp3","answer":"Quem mandou esta carta?"},
{"question":"Who taught you that?","sound":"whotaughtyouthat.mp3","answer":"Quem te ensinou isso?"},
{"question":"Who taught you?","sound":"whotaughtyou.mp3","answer":"Quem te ensinou?"},
{"question":"Who was that?","sound":"whowasthat.mp3","answer":"Quem era?"},
{"question":"Who was your teacher?","sound":"whowasyourteacher.mp3","answer":"Quer foi teu professor/tua professora?"},
{"question":"Who won?","sound":"whowon.mp3","answer":"Quem ganhou?"},
{"question":"Who would you like to speak to?","sound":"whowouldyouliketospeakto.mp3","answer":"Com quem você gostaria de falar?"},
{"question":"Who's calling?","sound":"whoscalling.mp3","answer":"Quem fala?"},
{"question":"Who's that man over there?","sound":"whosthatmanoverthere.mp3","answer":"Que é aquele homem alí?"},
{"question":"Whose book is that?","sound":"whosbookisthat.mp3","answer":"De quem é esse livro?"},
{"question":"Why are you laughing?","sound":"whyareyoulaughing.mp3","answer":"Quem está rindo?"},
{"question":"Why aren't you going?","sound":"whyarentyougoing.mp3","answer":"Por que você está indo?"},
{"question":"Why did you do that?","sound":"whydidyoudothat.mp3","answer":"Por que você fez isso?"},
{"question":"Why did you say that?","sound":"whydidyousaythat.mp3","answer":"Por que você disse isso?"},
{"question":"Why not?","sound":"whynot.mp3","answer":"Por que não?"},
{"question":"Will you call me a taxi please?","sound":"willyoucallmeataxiplease.mp3","answer":"Você me chama um táxi por favor?"},
{"question":"Will you hand me a towel please?","sound":"willyouhandmeatowelplease.mp3","answer":"Você me alcança uma toalha por favor?"},
{"question":"Will you pass me the salt please?","sound":"willyoupassmethesaltplease.mp3","answer":"Você me passa o sal por favor?"},
{"question":"Will you put this in the car for me?","sound":"willyouputthisinthecarforme.mp3","answer":"Você poria isso no carro pra mim?"},
{"question":"Will you remind me?","sound":"willyouremindme.mp3","answer":"Você me lembra?"},
{"question":"Will you take me home?","sound":"willyoutakemehome.mp3","answer":"Você me leva pra casa?"},
{"question":"Would you ask him to call me back please?","sound":"wouldyouaskhimtocallmebackplease.mp3","answer":"Você pede a ele pra me ligar de volta por favor?"},
{"question":"Would you ask him to come here?","sound":"wouldyouaskhimtocomehere.mp3","answer":"Você pede a ele para vir aqui?"},
{"question":"Would you like a glass of water?","sound":"wouldyoulikeaglassofwater.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de um copo com água?"},
{"question":"Would you like coffee or tea?","sound":"wouldyoulikecoffeeortea.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de café ou chá?"},
{"question":"Would you like some water?","sound":"wouldyoulikesomewater.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de um pouco de água?"},
{"question":"Would you like some wine?","sound":"wouldyoulikesomewine.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de um pouco de vinho?"},
{"question":"Would you like something to drink?","sound":"wouldyoulikesomethingtodrink.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de algo para beber?"},
{"question":"Would you like something to eat?","sound":"wouldyoulikesomethingtoeat.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de algo para comer?"},
{"question":"Would you like to buy this?","sound":"wouldyouliketobuythis.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de comprar isto?"},
{"question":"Would you like to go for a walk?","sound":"wouldyouliketogoforawalk.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de fazer um passeio?"},
{"question":"Would you like to have dinner with me?","sound":"wouldyouliketohavedinnerwithme.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de jantar comigo?"},
{"question":"Would you like to rent a movie?","sound":"wouldyouliketorentamovie.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de alugar um filme?"},
{"question":"Would you like to watch TV?","sound":"wouldyouliketowatchtv.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de assistir TV?"},
{"question":"Would you like water or milk?","sound":"wouldyoulikewaterormilk.mp3","answer":"Você gostaria de água ou leite?"},
{"question":"Would you take a message please?","sound":"wouldyoumakeamessageplease.mp3","answer":"Você anotaria a mensagem por favor?"},
{"question":"Yes, really.","sound":"yesreally.mp3","answer":"Sim, de verdade."},
{"question":"Yes.","sound":"yes.mp3","answer":"Sim."},
{"question":"You have a very nice car.","sound":"youhaveaverynicecar.mp3","answer":"Você tem um carro legal."},
{"question":"You look like my sister.","sound":"youlooklikemysister.mp3","answer":"Você se parece com minha irmã."},
{"question":"You look tired.","sound":"youlooktierd.mp3","answer":"Você parece cansado/a."},
{"question":"You speak English very well.","sound":"youspeakenglishverywell.mp3","answer":"Você fala inglês muito bem."},
{"question":"Your children are very well behaved.","sound":"yourechildrenareverywellbehaved.mp3","answer":"Teus filhos se comportam muito bem."},
{"question":"Your daughter.","sound":"youredaughter.mp3","answer":"Sua filha."},
{"question":"Your house is very nice.","sound":"yourehouseisverynice.mp3","answer":"Sua casa é muito legal."},
{"question":"Your things are all here.","sound":"yourethingsareallthere.mp3","answer":"Tuas coisas estão todas aqui."},
{"question":"You're beautiful.","sound":"yourebeautiful.mp3","answer":"Você é bonito/a"},
{"question":"You're right.","sound":"youreright.mp3","answer":"Você está certo/a."},
{"question":"You're smarter than him.","sound":"youresmarterthanhim.mp3","answer":"Você é mais esperto/a que ele."},
{"question":"You're very nice.","sound":"youreverynice.mp3","answer":"Você é muito gentil/legal."},
{"question":"You're very smart.","sound":"youreverysmart.mp3","answer":"Você é bem esperto."},
{"question":"You're welcome.","sound":"yourewelcome.mp3","answer":"De nada."}
]
